Damn, overtaken again.
可恶 又被超车了
Why didn't you rent a better car?
借车的话就借好一点的
Seriously!
是的啊
It would be better to take the train, wouldn't it?
坐电车就好了啊
Shut up!
吵死了
It was because the client asked me to bring all of you along that I rented this big car to hold everyone!
是委托人让我把你们一起带来我才借了能装下那么多人的车
Five seconds left.
还有5秒
What?
什么？
If you don't turn right now,
现在不马上打方向盘的话
we'll crash into the wall in five seconds.
5秒后会猛撞上墙壁的
What?
什么？
Wow, amazing!
哇 好厉害啊
It looks like a castle!
好像就是城堡一样啊
Then, does the emperor or something live here?
那么是不是帝王什么的住在这里啊
Idiot! As if he would!
笨蛋 怎么可能这样嘛
This is just a hotel.
因为这是酒店啊
It's right in front of Miracle Land.
这里是MIRACLE LAND的正前方
If someone always lived here and spent lots of money in Miracle Land,
长期居住在此并且在MIRACLE LAND挥金如土
it wouldn't be strange to consider that rich person an emperor.
如果是富可敌国的有钱人的话也是可以想像的
Say, I heard this hotel is going to welcome its 100,000th guest, right?
说起来这个酒店进驻的客人超过了10万啊
Really? Then it's really successful, huh?
是嘛 相当的繁盛啊
I'd like to see for myself.
我想看看啊
Well, excuse me.
那个 打扰了
Are you Detective Mouri?
您是毛利侦探吗
Yes, I am.
是的
We were expecting you.
我正在等您
I'm your client's secretary, Takada.
我是委托人的秘书叫高田
Let's get back to business. Please come this way.
言归正传 这边请
Take care of that car.
你去停下车
Yes, sir.
是
Please, this way.
请 是这里
Wow, amazing!
哇 好厉害啊
We can see all of Miracle Land from here.
看起来MIRACLE LAND可以一览无遗啊
Oh, I'm sorry.
啊 非常抱歉
Please sit on these seats and wait for a while.
请坐在椅子上等待一会儿
Huh?
咦？
Hey, be quiet and sit down.
喂 安静点给我坐在椅子上
Fine.
是
Then, please wait a moment.
那么请稍等
Awesome!
真厉害
I'm so excited!
好兴奋啊
What's wrong, Conan?
怎么了 柯南
Somehow, it seems that this chair doesn't match this room.
总觉得这个椅子不太配这个房间啊
Come to think of it, you're right.
嗯 这么说的话是这样的啊
Maybe they had to cut the budget.
是不是削减预算了啊
How could somewhere like this have budget cuts?
怎么可能有这样的事啊
After all, this is a luxurious hotel.
这是很豪华的酒店啊
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
让你们久等了
These are why we asked you to bring the kids here.
让孩子们来是为了给他们这个啊
What is this, exactly?
这个到底是什么
These are free pass IDs for Miracle Land.
这个是MIRACLE LAND的免费通行ID
While Mr. Mouri is solving the case, we thought it would be nice to let the kids have fun at Miracle Land.
毛利先生在解决案件的时候 我们想让孩子们在MIRACLE LAND好好玩玩
Could it be that the client is the owner of this place?
委托人不会是这里的拥有者吧
No, it's not like that.
不 不是这样的
This suite is rented on an annual basis.
这个套房是通过年付租的
Huu? That's awesome.
啊 好厉害啊
Everyone, please put them on your wrists.
各位 请把它戴在手腕上
Fasten them tightly, just in case you lose them.
好好的戴着不要掉了哦
If you lose it, we can't give you another one.
掉了的话是不会在发一个的哦
Mr. Mouri, you too. Please wear it.
毛利先生也请戴上
Don't bother, I'm not going to the amusement park.
不了 我不去游乐园的
Don't say that.
不要这么说嘛
If you finish your work early, you will be able to enjoy yourself with everyone e lse.
工作早点结束的话就可以和大家一起享受了
I see.
是吗
These IDs are valid today, until 10:00 p.m., the closing time of Miracle Land.
这个ID在今天一天到MIRACLE LAND的闭园时间晚上10点前是有效的
All meals and drinks are free.
食物和饮料全都是免费的
Please enjoy yourself!
请尽情享受
That's great!
太好了
Thank you!
谢谢
Let's go, Conan.
走吧 柯南
OK.
嗯
Please stay here.
你就请留在这里
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
Why?
为什么啊
Don't tell me you're the 100,000th guest of this hotel?
难道你正好是这个酒店的第10万名客人吗
Well, something like that.
啊 差不多就是这样的
Really?
真的吗？
That's so nice!
真好啊
Then let's get in line now.
那么我们先去排队吧
It's pretty normal to wait in line for two hours for the Super Snake.
SUPER SNAKE等2个小时是很平常的事
Indeed.
嗯 是的啊
Then I'll see you later, Conan.
那么柯南待会见了
OK.
嗯
Hey, what does the 100,000th guest get?
喂 第10万名客人会得到什么啊
At least it won't be an eel rice bowl.
肯定不会是馒鱼饭的啦
Ah, you're so lucky.
啊 你小子真幸运啊
There must be some kind of big surprise for the 100,000th guest.
第10万名客人的话肯定有很棒的服务
I just don't want to be interrupted.
只是不想被打扰
What do you mean by interrupted?
打扰是指？
The 100,000th guest is not me, right?
第10万名不是我吧
The confetti from the hydrangea is all over the ground in front of the hotel.
花绣球的彩色纸屑都落在酒店的门口了
Oh, really?
是这样吗
Yes.
是的
The 100,000th guest came about an hour ago.
第10万名的是一小时左右前来的客人
Then why did you make this brat stay?
那么为什么留下了这家伙
It was client's request.
委托人要求这么做的
Hey, what's this?
喂 这是什么
What's going on?
怎么回事
Thank you very much for coming.
大驾光临 非常感谢
I'm your client.
我是委托人
Please forgive me for hiding my face in the shadows without explanation.
请原谅因为某种原因而把脸藏在阴暗处的无礼
The reason I asked you to come here today is because there is a case waiting for you to solve.
今天请您来是想让您解决某个事件
What case do you want me to solve?
想让我解决什么事件
Well, it's also a part of your job to figure this out.
哼 找出这个也是你们的工作
Huh?
咦？
Now I'll give you a few hints.
接下来我会出几个提示
Please use this as a basis for your reasoning through and solving this case.
请以此为基础进行推理并解决事件
But why did you hire me?
可是为什么要请我呢
You're the fifth detective I've hired.
你是我第五个委托的侦探了
What about the first four?
那么前面的4个人呢
One of them is still investigating.
一个人还在调查
Two have given up.
两个人放弃了
And one who couldn't solve the case is here.
还有一个解决不了事件正在这里
Ryu!
龙！
You know him?
认识的人吗
He's a detective I used to work with before.
他是以前和我共事过的侦探
Didn't I give you the investigation report?
调查报告书不是交给你了吗
How long are you going to keep me locked up here?
你打算把我关在这里关到什么时候啊
Hurry up and let me out!
快点让我出去
Detective Ryu, you were unable to solve the case.
龙侦探 你解决不了事件
What did you say?
你说什么
An incompetent detective has no right to live.
无能的侦探没有活着的资格
What is this?
这是什 什么
It's the same ID as ours.
和我们一样的ID啊
Yeah...
嗯
Damn, what's wrong with this?
可恶 这个怎么了
It doesn't matter. There's no pain.
不要紧的 没有痛苦
You'll be at peace in an instant.
一瞬间就快活了
Could it be that the thing that made Mogi and Souda disappear is...
难 难道茂木和枪田的消失就是…
Farewell, Detective Ryu.
永别了 龙侦探
Hey, wait, wait!
喂 等等 等等
Damn it!
可恶
Composition Four, or plastic explosive, was built into it...
COMPOSITION FORM也就是塑胶炸弹被融合在了里面
In the Miracle Land ID that Detective Ryu was wearing on his wrist.
在龙侦探手腕上戴着的MIRACLE LAND的ID里面啊
You bastard!
你小子
Who are Mogi and Souda mentioned by Ryu?
刚才龙说的茂木和枪田是什么
Well, they were two detectives who were well- known all over the world...
嗯 是被世间极度夸奖的两位名侦探啊
And two idiots who wasted my precious time.
他们是浪费了我宝贵时间的愚蠢的家伙
The deadline for you is 10:00 tonight.
给你们的时间是到今晚10点
Please find the truth about something before then.
到那时为止请找到某个事件的真相
If you can't solve the case by the deadline,
如果时间到了而没有解开事件
your IDs will also explode.
你们的ID也会爆炸
You will follow in Detective Ryu's footsteps.
会追随龙侦探之后而去
What?!
什么
Give it up.
放弃这么做吧
Such small amounts of external power can't make this ID come off.
一点点外部力量是取不下这个ID的
Besides, if you take it off before I deactivate it,
如果在我没有解除的时候脱下来的话
it will explode immediately.
会马上爆炸的
You bastard...
你小子
Ran!
兰
Right.
是啊
What about Ran and the other's IDs?
兰她们呢 她们戴的ID呢
The children's IDs are almost the same as yours.
孩子们的ID和你们的ID差不多是相同的东西
What do you mean?
你说什么
Almost.
差不多
Their IDs have an additional function.
他们的ID里面多追加了一个功能
This is a diagram of Miracle Land.
这是MIRACLE LAND的示意图
There are multiple sensors installed at the border of Miracle Land.
在MIRACLE LAND的边界处安装了几个探测器
Whenever their IDs enter Miracle Land,
他们的ID只要进入MIRACLE LAND
the sensors will sense it,
探测器就会感知到
and the detonator will be turned on.
会把起爆装置放到ON上面
If any one of them wants to exit the Miracle Land and passes by the sensors again,
想离开MIRACLE LAND而再次通过探测器的话
their IDs will explode at that exact moment.
就会与此同时爆炸
It would be troublesome to track them each individually.
一个个的追踪他们很麻烦啊
So please forgive me for doing this.
所以请让我这么做吧
Ran!
兰
Haibara, can you hear me?
灰原 听得到吗
Haibara!
灰原
Damn it!
可恶
What?
什么
Haibara, don't go in!
灰原 不要进去
What's wrong?
怎么了
I don't have time to talk too much. Bring everyone out.
不多说了 把大家带出来
Don't go in!
不要进去
Even though you say so,
就算这么说
we've already been inside.
已经进去了
You are a VIP, right?
您是VIP啊
This kind of IDs is only issued to special guests.
这个ID是只发给特别的客人的
Is that so?
是这样的啊
Please enjoy yourself.
好好的享受吧
Thank you.
谢谢
What happened?
发生了什么事？
I'll contact you again.
我会再联系你的
Ran?
兰呢
Damn it!
可恶
If you solve the case by 10:00 tonight and find the culprit for me,
今晚10点前解决事件为我找出犯人的话
I'll pay you however much you wish.
我会付你你所满意的费用
But if you can't solve the case within the time limit, I'll detonate all of the IDs.
可是要是不能在规定时间内解决事件的话我就会让ID爆炸
Take me to that man!
带我到那个男人那里去
Right now!
现在马上!!
I can't!
不行的啊
Because I don't know where he is either.
因为我也不知道他在哪里
What are you talking about?
你说什么
Mr. Mouri. Your actions are all being monitored.
毛利先生 你们的行动都被监视着
I've built a GPS into your ID.
我在ID里面加入了GPS
It will do you no good to run to the police.
就算跑去找警察也是没用的
Does that mean you'll press the detonation switch, you bastard?
就是说你会按下炸弹按钮是吗… 你这个混蛋
Talking for too long is a waste of time.
长时间说话只会浪费时间
The first hint.
第一个提示
I'm only going to say it once.
我只说一遍
Listen carefully.
好好听着
TAKA 3- 8.
TAKA 3-8
What is this?
这是什么
Tell me again.
给我再说一遍
I told you I'd only say it once.
我应该说过我只说一遍的
There are 12 hours left until the deadline.
到时限为止还有12个小时
Can you solve this mystery for me?
能为我解开这个谜吗
For my sake and for the sake of the children.
为了我也为了孩子们
Damn it!
可恶
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
Please take this.
请收下这个
This is a hotline to the client.
这是和委托人之间的热线
You can't call the client directly, even though I called it that.
虽然这么说可是你们是不能打给委托人的
It's only for receiving instructions from the client.
这只是用于接收委托人的指示的
After solving the case,
解决完事件后
call me using the number in this phone,
在打了存在这个电话里的我的电话后
and then come back here.
请回到这里
So we can listen to the truth carefully.
让我们慢慢的听一下真相吧
I am Shinichi Kudo, high school detective.
我是高中生侦探--工藤新一
When I was at the theme park with my childhood friend, Ran Mouri,
我和青梅竹马的同班同学毛利兰去游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed a suspicious exchange made by a man in black.
目击了黑衣男子的可疑的交易现场
I was too preoccupied with watching the deal go down,
专注的看着交易的我
and didn't notice another accomplice approaching from behind.
没有注意到从背后接近的另外一个同伴
He forced me to take a kind of poison by force.
我被那个男人灌下了毒药
When I woke up,
醒来之后
my body had become that of a child.
身体变小了
If they found out that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
如果让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着的话
they would definitely come after me,
他们还会来要我的命
or even hurt the people close to me.
而且还会给周围的人带来灾害
So at the suggestion of Professor Agasa, I concealed my true identity.
在阿笠博士的建议下决定隐藏真实身份的我
When Ran asked for my name, I took the name of Conan Edogawa.
在被兰问及名字的时候一下子自命名为--江户川柯南
In order to collect information about those guys,
为了得到那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran, whose father is a detective.
住进了父亲是侦探的兰的家里
The only ones who know my true identity are
知道我真实身份的有
Professor Agasa,
阿笠博士
my parents,
我的父母
Heiji Hattori, a high school detective from Kansai,
西之高中生侦探的服部平次
and Ai Haibara, my classmate.
同班同学的灰原哀
Professor Agasa has made many inventions for me, since my body became smaller.
阿笠博士为身体变小的我制作了很多新发明
Haibara was once a member of the Black Organization,
灰原是黑衣组织的同伙
but when she escaped from the organization,
可是从组织逃出来的时候
she took the same poison that I took.
吃了和我被灌下的毒药同样的药物
So she reverted to childhood too.
身体变小了
There is another person.
还有一个人
Kaito Kiddo.
怪盗基德
Whenever he shows up,
一和那家伙缠在一起
things get troublesome.
就会变成件很麻烦的事
My body may have shrunk,
就算身体变小了
but my mind is as sharp as ever.
头脑还是一样的
I am the famous detective who can solve any case.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相只有一个
Damn it!
可恶
What's up with this traffic jam?
这个堵车怎么回事
My daughter's life is on the line!
这可关系到我女儿的性命啊
- So don't leave Miracle Land! - Hurry up and move!
所以绝对不要从MIRACLE LAND出来 快点给我动起来
If you leave that area of the Miracle Land, the IDs will explode.
要是从MIRACLE LAND那个区域出来的话ID就会爆炸
Of course, don't play Super Snake either!
当然SUPER SNAKE也一样
Because the most attractive part of that Jet Booster is that it will go out over the sea as part of the ride.
因为那个JET BOOSTER最吸引人的地方就是在途中会飞到海那边去
Hey, are you listening, Haibara?
喂 你在听吗 灰原
Yes, I got it.
嗯 我知道了
If you don't solve the case by 10:00 tonight,
今晚10点前要是不能解决事件的话
you and I will both be blown into pieces, right?
我和你都会粉身碎骨的吧
Isn't this interesting?
这不是很有趣吗
Interesting? You...
居然说有趣 你啊
Hey, Haibara, what are you doing?
喂 灰原 你在干什么
Come over here quickly!
快点过来啊
Then our lives are in your hands, Great Detective!
那么我们的性命就交给你了 名侦探
But I don't understand anything!
可是完全不明白啊
What's that TAKA 3- 8?
那个是什么啊 TAKA 3-8
This can also be read as 3 minus 8, right?
这个也能读做3 8啊
So TAKA is a road name?
那么TAKA是街道名？
Yes, and 3-8 equals -5.
嗯 而且3-8=-5
If we remove the equal sign,
去掉等号的话
then it becomes 3-8-5.
不就变成了3 8 5吗
Got it, it's Takashima District.
有了 是高岛区
You mean the 3rd street of Takashima District, huh?
就是说是高岛区3号街吧
Hey, where's the 3rd street?
喂 3号街在哪里啊
There's no such a place.
没有
What?
什么
There's no 3rd street in Takashima District.
没有啊 高岛区3号街
What did you say? Let me take a look!
你说什么 给我看
Damn it!
可恶
We gotta start over again?
又要从头开始想了吗
Maybe not.
可能不是那样的
I heard the street names may have been changed due to redevelopment work.
据说这附近因为重新开发 街道名改过了
3-8-5 in Takashima District?
高岛区的3-8-5吗？
Yes.
嗯
Have the street names around here changed due to the redevelopment?
这附近是不是因为重新开发 街道名改过了？
That's because it became Minatomirai
因为变成未来港了啊
There was the 3rd street before.
3号街有的啊
Do you have a map?
有地图吗
Yes.
有
But does this place really have anything to do with that case?
可是这种地方真的和某个事件有什么关系吗
We have to believe it does, don't we?
只有认为有关系了啊 不是这样吗
Speaking of which, why do I have to stay with a schoolboy like you?
说起来为什么要你这样的小学生特意和我在一起啊
Because he thought you weren't reliable by yourself, I guess.
难道不是认为叔叔一个人不可靠吗
Indeed, it's strange.
确实很奇怪
Why did he let just me work with Mr. Mouri?
为什么只有让我和大叔一起行动呢
Why on earth?
到底是为什么
What's that?
什 什么
Who? Who is it?
谁 是谁
You can't live here.
这里不能住了
This house will be torn down next week.
下周这房子就要被拆掉了
Must be hard for you with a kid, huh?
你也够呛啊 还带着个孩子
What? No, no, no.
啊？  错了错了错了
Of course not.
当然了
Sir, have you been living here long?
叔叔你一直住在这里吗
Yes, since this hotel went bankrupt 2 years ago.
嗯 从旅馆倒闭的2年前开始
Has there been anything strange lately?
最近有没有什么奇怪的事呢
Anything at all?
什么都可以
Let me see. Oh, yeah, they said there was a giant white bird who flew over here.
这个啊 对了 据说有巨大的白鸟飞过这里
A giant bird?
巨大的鸟？
It flew right in front of the sun!
从太阳的前面一下子飞过去啊
When did this happen?
这是什么时候的事
It was my birthday, April 4th.
是我的生日的4月4日
A weird car parked there that morning.
那天早晨就有奇怪的车停在那里
And then, the real estate agent came and sealed off that basement.
房地产商过来封锁了这里下面的地下室
Weird car?
奇怪的车是？
There are not many cars here.
这里不太有车来的啊
When I went out in the morning,
早晨出去的时候
there was a brand new car parked in the courtyard.
那里的庭院中还停着崭新的车
But when I came back in the evening,
可是傍晚回来一看
it had turned into a second- hand car in shambles.
变成了破破烂烂的二手车了
At night, that car had its parts taken, leaving only the skeleton.
这车晚上也被卸掉了零件变成了一付骨架了
What's with that locked basement?
封锁了地下室是怎么一回事
The basement was a machine room.
地下是机器室
I guess he was gonna sell those machines for money.
卖掉机器想换成钱吧
About what time was that?
这大概是几点的时候
It was late afternoon.
是傍晚
What... What's going on?
怎 怎么回事
Hey, kid, what's wrong?
喂 小鬼 怎么了
So you're here?
什么嘛 在这里啊
Geez, don't scare me, okay?
真是的 不要吓我啊
This is...
这个是？
What?
怎么了
I found this.
发现了这样的东西
What's this?
这是什么啊
This is...
这个是！
A mask and gloves.
蒙面和手套
And a Government pistol?
还有GOVERMENT手枪
A receipt?
是收据啊
April 4th, Yokohama City.
4月4日 横滨新都市
Mr. Mouri.
叔叔
Isn't April 4th the day that guy said there was a weird car parked here?
4月4日不就是刚才那个人说的有奇怪的车子停在这里的日子吗
Yes, he said the car changed that day.
嗯 他说早晚车子变换了
What? Changed?
什么？ 变换了？
Got it!
我知道了
A fugitive changed cars here!
逃跑的人在这里换车啊
This fugitive is the culprit who did something with this mask and this Government gun.
是用这个蒙面和GOVERMENT手枪做了什么的犯人啊
Next is to find out what happened on April 4th.
接下来是搞清楚4月4日发生了什么事件
If we know that,
那个知道了的话
the rest will be easy.
接下来就简单了
What are those guys doing?
那些家伙干什么
Hand... Handgun!
手 手枪
It's clear that they're no ordinary people.
可以确认不是一般的人
Do you think they're here for the bag?
他们不会是来取回这个包的吧
It's possible.
有可能啊
Okay, I got it.
好了 我明白了
You jump out and distract those guys.
你快跳出去引开那些家伙
In the meantime, I'll get in the car and help you get out of here.
在这个空隙我乘上车子来帮助你然后逃出这里
I'm telling you it doesn't matter.
我说过不要紧了
Those guys won't just shoot a kid out of nowhere.
那些家伙不会突然对一个孩子开枪的
What's the matter, kid?
怎么了 你小子
Don't you believe me?
不相信我说的话吗
No, I don't.
不相信
Just get out of here!
别烦了 给我出去
Wait!
给我等等
That's what I'm afraid of.
我就是说这个嘛
Damn it, at this critical moment! This stupid car!
可恶 在这个关键的时候 这个破车
Arrest them!
给我逮捕
You said arrest?
你说逮捕
Are you guys...
你们这些家伙
Police officers?
是警察!?
It really is a huge bird as big as a person!
真是个和人一样巨大的鸟啊
What?
什么
It's that guy.
是那个家伙
The one who surrounded the dark world with his white wings
凭借白色的翅膀包围黑暗的世界
is Kaito Kiddo!
是怪盗基德
Kiddo?
基德
Inspector, we've found Kiddo!
警部 发现基德
Now he's on the roof of the Miyama Building, above the devil statue!
现在在深山大厦的屋顶恶魔像的上面
Okay, I got it.
好 知道了
President Miyama, Kiddo has appeared.
深山社长 基德现身了
I see, let's take a look.
我知道了 去看看吧
Even Kiddo won't be able to break this new security system.
哼 这次的防范系统就算是基德也是怎么也破坏不了的啊
Kiddo!
基德
Damn it!
可恶
This is Yokomizo.
我是横沟
Kiddo is running away from the Miyama Building towards the Landmark Tower.
基德从深山大厦朝着LANDMARK TOWER方向逃走了
Repeat.
重复一遍
Kiddo is running away towards Landmark Tower!
基德朝着LANDMARK TOWER逃走了
Go after him right now!
立即给我部署！
It looks like the police's stakeout was not that useful, huh?
看起来警方埋伏好像没有什么用处啊
But there are many kinds of security systems.
防范系统是各种各样的
Inspector Yokomizo!
横沟警部
We caught a man who seems to be Kiddo's accomplice.
我们抓住了好像是基德同伙的男人
We're bringing him to the station.
正在把他带到署里面来
Got it, I'll be right back.
知道了  我马上就回去
I told you, I'm not Kiddo's accomplice.
我说了嘛 我不是什么基德的同伙
I'm Kogoro Mouri!
是毛利小五郎啊
Not good.
不妙了
If this goes on...
这样下去的话
Your actions are all being monitored by monitors.
你们的行动都被监视器监视着
I've built a GPS into your ID.
我在ID里面加入了GPS
It will do you no good to run to the police.
就算跑去找警察也是没用的
ID number 1 and ID number 2 are now approaching Kanagawa Police Headquarters.
ID号码1和ID号码2正在朝着神奈川县警察总局而去
It's always exciting to hear that kind of voice, right?
听到了那个声音总觉得很兴奋啊
But I'm already tired of waiting in line.
可是我已经讨厌排队了
How much longer do we have to wait?
还要排多久啊
Well...
这个嘛
Let's say 3 people in line take up about one meter,
假设1米里面排着3个人
since there are about 150 meters in the line, there should be about 450 people.
因为有大约150米所以有450人
As Super Snake can hold 22 people each time,
因为SUPER SNAKE一次能乘坐22人
it will take about 20 rides to go through 450 people.
所以450人的话大约要20次
One ride, including the time to get on and off, takes about 10 minutes,
一次的时间包括上下车大约要10分钟
so it gonna take 200 minutes.
所以要200分钟
Then it's about 3 and a half hours.
大约要3小时半
Awesome, Mitsuhiko!
你太厉害了 光彦
We still have to wait that long?
还要等那么长的时间啊
I'm hungry.
我肚子饿了
If the Professor were here, he would give us some boring riddle to kill some time.
要是博士在的话就可以出冷笑话来消磨时间了
Indeed.
是啊
Then I'll be the one to give you the riddle today.
那么今天就由我来出猜谜吧
What? You will do it?
什么？ 兰来出吗
Can't I?
不可以吗
No! Go ahead! Go ahead!
不是的 快出快出
I guess there's no choice. We'll answer it.
没有办法了 我们来回答吧
Then here we go.
那么开始了
Miracle Land Riddle.
MIRACLE LAND猜谜
Everyone wants to ride the Super Snake.
大家最想乘坐的SUPER SNAKE
Then, out of you all, who is the most suitable for this ride?
那么在侦探团的中间谁最适合这个游乐设施呢
I know, the answer is Ai, isn't it?
我知道了 答案是小哀吧
Why?
为什么
Because Ai seems to like snakes.
因为小哀看起来很喜欢蛇
I hate snakes.
我很讨厌蛇哦
Wrong.
错了
Then it's me, right?
那么是我吧
I always wait for people, just like I wait for Super Snake.
和SUPER SNAKE一起总是不得不等啊
What's that?
那是什么啊
Did you forget that I waited for you at your house for a crazy long time
难道你忘了去公园的时候
when we went to the park?
去元太家的时候我一直在等啊
That's wrong too.
这个也错了
And you, Genta?
元太呢
It's me, right?
是我吧
Because snakes and eels are alike.
因为蛇和鳗鱼很像
I like eel rice bowls the most!
我最喜欢鳗鱼饭了
What a pity!
可惜啊
What happens to Genta who loves eel rice bowls so much?
喜欢馒鱼饭的元太怎么了？
Even if you ask me what happens...
就算说怎么了
I think I'm hungry.
好像肚子饿了
I see.
原来如此
The Japanese for "Snake" sounds like the English for "heavy".
SUPER SNAKE就是超级重 （日语中蛇（hebi）和heavy谐音）
Therefore, super heavy.
也就是非常重
So Kojima, the most heaviest of us, is the correct answer.
所以体重很重的小岛是正解
Bingo!
对了
I thought Ran's riddle would be something different.
我还想兰的谜语是与众不同的呢
In the end, it's still just a lame joke.
结果还是冷笑话啊
Hmm...
嗯
Ah! Conan?
啊 柯南
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Inspector Megure!
目暮警部
What happened to Mouri?
毛利到底怎么了
They said they arrested Kiddo's accomplice, is that true?
据说抓住了基德的共犯者吗？
Hmm, Nakamori.
嗯 中森
Megure, you rascal...
目暮这狸猫
Why are you here?
为什么你在这里
It seems that Mouri was arrested by mistake.
好像毛利被搞错逮捕了
What?
什么
So Kiddo's accomplice is that Sleeping Kogoro?
那么说是基德的共犯者就是那个沉睡的小五郎？
As a detective, I have a duty to keep my client's secrets.
侦探有为委托人保守秘密的义务
But if your client is Kiddo,
如果这个委托人是基德的话
aren't you an accomplice?
你不就是共犯者了吗？
But wait, why were the Kanagawa Police staking out that building?
可是为什么神奈川县警要埋伏在那栋大厦里呢
Because they received an advance notice from Kiddo.
因为从基德那里寄来了预告函啊
That building is the main office of Miyama Corporation.
那栋大厦是深山商事的总公司啊
On the top floor of the building, there were various jewels that President Miyama had collected.
在那栋大厦的最上层展示着社长深山作为兴趣收藏的宝石
But unlike last time,
可是这次和上次不同
nothing was taken.
什么也没有拿走
Did Kiddo get into that building before?
前次也被基德进入了吗
Yeah.
嗯
On April 4th of this year, a huge diamond was stolen.
今年的4月4日被偷走了很大的钻石
It seems that the security system has been upgraded,
因为好像升级了梦想的防范系统
in the end, Miyama was pretty pleased with this time.
在这次(基德来偷东西)的最后深山很高兴啊
April 4th?
4月4日
But I thought Yokomizo was in the first division of research department.
可是横沟应该是搜查一课的啊
Isn't Kiddo assigned to the second division?
负责基德的不是二课吗
Lately there has been a strange guy trying to kill Kiddo.
最近有奇怪的家伙要杀基德
Because we are related to him, some officers were even injured.
因为我们和他有关联还出现了伤者
So it seems that the first division came to help us.
所以好像让一课来协助我们
Oh, trying to kill Kiddo?
啊 要杀基德
Someone's calling. Sorry.
有人打电话来了 抱歉
Detective Mouri?
毛利侦探
No, Kudo?
不 是工藤吧
It's you, isn't it?
果然是你啊
High school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
高中生侦探 工藤新一
I was quite surprised that you came with Detective Mouri.
我很惊讶你和毛利侦探一起来了
In fact, I wanted to ask you to investigate for me.
其实也想请你来为我调查的
But I didn't know how to contact you.
可是我不知道怎么联络到你
Seem like you couldn't solve the case and went to the police, huh?
哼 解决不了事件去找警察了吗
No, we weren't trying to do that.
不是 不是去找的
In the ruined hotel, Detective Mouri was arrested by five police officers on a stakeout.
在废墟的旅馆中毛利侦探被埋伏的5名警察抓住了
Oh, you're really honest.
你很老实啊
This guy knew?
这家伙知道的啊
That there were police at that place?
那里有警察的事
Ah, forget it.
啊 算了
So what was in the hotel?
那么旅馆中有什么
We found a mask and pistol used for some crime.
发现了被认为是用于犯罪的蒙面和手枪
Well done, Kudo.
很好 工藤
So here's the second hint.
那么是第二个提示
Go to cafe terrace at night.
去夜间的露天咖啡馆
Cafe terrace at night?
夜间的露天咖啡馆？
You'll know where it is, if it's really you.
是你的话应该知道那是哪里吧
I will definitely solve this case!
事件一定会由我来解决
So disengage Ran and the others' IDs.
所以给我解开兰他们的ID
Hey, are you listening?
喂 你在听吗
Damn it!
可恶
The person you love...
爱着的人
How painful is it to lose the person you love?
失去爱着的人是怎样的痛苦
Please try hard to stop that thing from happening.
请你努力避免发生那样的事
Kudo.
工藤
Why?
为什么
Why does he know my true identity?
为什么那家伙知道我的真实身份
That guy...
那家伙
Who is that guy really?
那家伙是何方神圣?!
The line isn't moving at all, but my stomach is growling.
队列一点也没有前进可是肚子叫了
Right.
是的啊
Speaking of which, it's not even lunchtime yet.
说起来还没有到中午啊
Okay, I'll stand in line for you guys.
那么我来为你们排队
You can go and eat something.
你们去吃点什么吧
Is that really okay, Haibara?
这样好吗 灰原
But I feel bad for leaving Ai here alone.
可是小哀一个人很可怜啊
Really?
是吗？
Then I'll stay with Haibara.
那么我和灰原留下来
I'll stay too.
我也留下来
Then I'll stay too.
那么我也留下来
Are you guys stupid? That's no point if we all stay.
笨蛋 这样的话不就没有意义了吗
Then how about this?
那么这么吧
We'll take turns to stand in line every 30 minutes.
每30分钟交替排队
We can start with Ai, all right?
首先是小哀怎么样
Agreed!
赞成！
Then I'll see you in 30 minutes.
那么30分钟后哦
Okay!
是的
Sorry.
对不起哦
Please go on ahead.
请往前面排吧
How long can I keep this up?
这样能维持到什么时候啊
If I could disassemble one, I might be able to figure something out.
试着分解的话可能会知道点什么
It's not a simple explosive device.
这也不是个单纯的爆炸装置啊
I can't do anything here.
在这里什么也办不成啊
I see.
是吗
Oh, that's right.
哦 对了
I gave it a power-up.
我把它的能量增强了
Thank you.
THANK YOU
By the way, did you figure out?
说起来你知道了吗
Where is that cafe terrace at night?
夜间的露天咖啡馆在哪里
Yes.
嗯
Where exactly is it?
到底在哪里
The Cafe Terrace at Night was painted by Van Gogh in 1888.
（夜のカッフェテラス 即 阿尔夜间的露天咖啡座 The Cafe Terrace on the Place du Forum,Arles,at Night） 夜间的露天咖啡馆是凡高在1888年画的
It depicts a dim gas lamp illuminating a cafe terrace, near a street where horse-drawn carriages come and go.
（文森特·凡·高　创作于1888年9月 目前收藏于荷兰欧特娄的国立克罗-米勒博物馆中） 那个在淡淡的煤气灯下的露天咖啡馆 后面有马车行进过来的风景画
If we're talking about gas lamp and horse- drawn carriages,
煤气灯和马车的话
the only answer is the carriage road in Japan that was the first to be equipped with gas lamps.
那只有是在日本最初装上煤气灯的马车道了
The energy is too high, professor.
能量增强得太多了 博士
Haibara!
灰原
Here.
给
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
Huh? We're still here?
咦？ 还只是排在这里吗
I think my estimation was off.
好像是我刚才计算错误了吧
It's our turn now.
换我们了哦
If you would.
拜托了
So cute, Ran.
好可爱啊 兰
Your face was just like a child's.
这种像孩子一般的表情
Sonoko?
园子
What are you doing here?
你为什么在这里啊
Look, the Red Castle Hotel over there.
你看 那里的RED CASTEL HOTEL
I heard that they're having a party tonight to celebrate their 100,000th guest.
说是那里的客人今天突破了10万今晚要举行宴会
Because that hotel was funded by my father,
因为那个酒店好像是我爸爸造的
so I came to this amusement park to kill some time before the party begins.
所以我就来到这个游乐园消磨时间一直到宴会的时候
Huh? Where did you pick this up?
咦？ 你这个是在哪里捡到的
It's not like that!
不是的
It's from one of my dad's clients.
这个是爸爸的委托人给我们的东西
What? That client must be some big shot!
什么？ 有那么有地位的委托人啊
I didn't find my ID, so I thought I might have dropped it.
我的ID找不到了所以我想是不是掉了啊
Oh, right!
啊 对了
You and the kids were also invited to the party, right?
因为兰和这些孩子也被招待去宴会了
How about we both go to Red Castle first?
不如我们两个先到RED CASTEL去吧
These kids are wearing for their IDs,
如果孩子们戴着ID的话
so it's okay to leave them here.
不去管他们也不要紧的
Especially this kid,
特别是这个孩子
she looks very reliable.
看起来很可靠的
But...
可是
Right now, there is a cake buffet at the restaurant there.
现在在那里的餐厅中有自助蛋糕
With this ID,
有这个ID的话
you are free to go in and out of Miracle Land.
可以自由进出MIRACLE LAND的
What's in here, exactly?
这里到底有什么呢
Don't move!
不要动
Hattori?
服部
How was that? Were you scared?
怎么样 吓了一跳吧？
Shut up.
喽嗦
This is a good time to bump into each other.
我们正好在一个好地方碰到了
You're pretty smart, huh?
你不是很聪明吗
No way, Kudo? You too?
什么 工藤 你也是啊
So you were also...
那么你也是？
Yeah, Kazuha is being held hostage.
嗯 和叶被当做人质了
But she doesn't know anything about it. She's just having fun at the theme park.
不过她本人什么也不知道在那个游乐园悠闲得玩着呢
The number you dialed
您所拨打的电话
is out of service or powered off.
不在服务区或者没有开机
We are unable to connect you at this time.
现在不能连接上
Geez. What the hell?
真是的 什么嘛
He told me to have fun and wait as he had something to sort out quickly.
明明说过“马上可以搞定的 随便玩玩等着吧”
I really feel like I'm Ran waiting for Kudo.
真是变成了等待工藤兰的心情了
Huh? Kazuha?
咦？ 和叶?!
Ran? Is that you?
不是兰吗
Kazuha, long time no see.
和叶 好久不见啊
So you're here too?
你来这里了啊
Where's Hattori?
服部呢
Work... Work.
工作啊 工作
I see.
是吗？
So boring.
好无聊啊
Huh? Kazuha?
啊？ 和叶
Sonoko!
园子啊
Right, we're going to a cake buffet.
对了 我们接下来要去吃自助蛋糕
Wanna come?
一起去吗
I love cakes!
我最喜欢蛋糕了
Then, let's go!
那么 快走快走
Hmm!
嗯
Hey, Ran, we're leaving.
喂 兰 走了
Wait!
等等
I see...
这样啊
So she has been taken hostage too.
那位姐姐也被作为人质了啊
Yeah, not only Ran.
嗯 不仅是兰
There are four children too.
还有4个孩子
Also, the client seems to know that I'm Shinichi Kudo.
而且 好像委托人把我认为是工藤新一
Are you saying that he knows your true identity?
就是说知道你的真实身份？
I'm not sure yet.
这还不知道
Hey, you think it's because they've figured out about that drug shrinking you?
喂 不会是你的身体被灌了药后变小的事败露的吧？
That black organization...
被那个黑衣组织的
Hey!
喂
What's wrong?
怎么了
The mask, the pistol, and the getaway car.
蒙面 手枪和逃走用的车辆
I see!
这样啊
An attack on an armored car?
袭击现金运钞车
Yeah.
是的
Is that what he was talking about?
那家伙说的就是那个吧
Maybe.
可能吧
Can I have a minute?
占用点时间可以吗
What is it, kid?
什么事 小孩子
Has that armored car ever been attacked?
那个现金运钞车被袭击过吗
Yes, it has.
嗯 有的啊
I think it was on April 4th.
好像是4月4日的事情吧
Since you run a business here, you must have been questioned by the police, right?
在这里开店的话总归被警察调查过吧
Can you tell us the details?
能不能详细的和我们说说呢
Yeah.
可以
It was right around this time of day.
正好是现在的这个时间
Don't move.
不准动
Stay still!
给我老师点
It all happened in a flash.
真的是一瞬间的事啊
I couldn't even tell if it was a dream or reality.
都分不清是梦还是现实了
That means it was perfectly executed., right?
就是说手法很巧妙是吧
Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢阿姨
Wait a minute!
等一下
Kids, today is the worst day of your lives.
孩子们 今天是你们人生当中最坏的一天
You should go home and sleep.
回家睡觉去吧
Yeah, I will, but only after I make it the best day of my life.
嗯 我会的 不过是在把它变成人生中最好的一天之后
See you.
再见
Don't go running off! I've been looking for you!
不要随便到处乱跑 我在找你啊
Ouch!
难受啊
Forget it, this is not the time to be fighting.
算了算了 现在不是吵架的时候吧
Why is that dark-skinned brat from Osaka here too?
为什么大阪的黑皮小子也在这里啊
For the same reason as you.
和你一样的理由啊
Mouri.
毛利
Give me back the client's cell phone!
还给我委托人那里拿来的手机
It's about time to tell us the truth, isn't it?
该向我们说说真相了吧
Well, even if you say it that way...
啊 就算说是真相
There are limits to what a detective can do alone, right?
侦探的行动是有界限的吧
Wouldn't it be better to let us take care of it quickly?
快点把它交给我们不是很好吗
This is Mouri.
我是毛利
So it's Detective Mouri this time?
这次是毛利侦探啊
Forget it, now you're on the carriage road?
算了 现在在马车道吧
Yeah.
是的
I thought I've told you not to be so close to the police.
不可以啊 和警察关系搞得这么好
Are you watching me?
你这家伙 在监视吗
That one?
那个吗
Are you going to break the agreement, Mouri?
你打算违反约定吗 毛利
Definitely not!
没有这样的事
This is force majeure!
这是不可抗力啊
Mouri, who are you talking to?
毛利你到底和谁在说话
Idiot! Idiot!
笨蛋 笨蛋
Get lost, you incompetent cops!
无能的警察快消失
What did he say?
他说什么
Idiot! Idiot!
笨蛋 笨蛋
- Get lost, you incompetent cops! - What's wrong with that doll?
无能的警察快消失 -可恶 那个玩具娃娃怎么了
- Get lost, you incompetent cops! - Hey!
无能的警察快消失 -喂
- This is not looking good, isn't it? - Idiot! Idiot!
不会很糟吗 -笨蛋 笨蛋
Dangerous! Get away from the doll, it's gonna explode!
危险 快从那个玩具娃娃那里离开 会爆炸的 无能的警察快消失
What?
什么？
10 seconds to explosion.
爆炸前10秒
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4...
9 8 7 6 5 4
- 3, 2, 1 - Damn it!
3 2 1 -可恶
Mama!
妈妈
Yokomizo!
横沟
Send an ambulance! Be quick!
快叫救护车 火速
You brat!
你这小子
Next time it will be those kids' turn!
下次就轮到那些小孩子喽
Mouri!
毛利
What's wrong?
怎么了
Somehow, this ID has been flashing since a while ago.
这个ID从刚才开始不知道为什么变的一闪一闪的忽亮忽灭
Mine too.
我的也是
Do you know anything about this, Sonoko?
园子知道什么吗
This is my first time seeing this.
我是第一次看见这种情况
Go ask the staff ahead and we'll know.
去问一下出口处的工作人员不就知道了吗
Geez.
真是的
He didn't even notice such a huge bomb right in front of him.
那种程度的爆炸都不能察觉
What on earth is wrong with the police nowadays?
最近的警察到底怎么了啊
What did you say?
你说什么
Isn't it your fault that this happened?
不是因为你的错才这样的吗
Let go of me! There's no evidence of that!
放开我 没有这样的证据啊
To be honest, you're troublesome.
说白了 很麻烦啊
Stop bothering me. Okay?
不要再纠缠我了
What?
什么
I'm glad I left the police.
辞了警察真是上策啊
I wanna live a long life.
我可是想长寿的啊
Hey, let's go.
喂 走了
OK.
嗯
Inspector, is that all right?
警部 这样可以吗
It's all right.
可以
Ran and the children are being held hostage at Miracle Land.
兰和孩子们在MIRACLE LAND被作为了人质
They're wearing IDs on their wrists that will explode if they leave.
她们手腕上戴者的ID一走出MIRACLE LAND就会爆炸
Please protect Ran and the others discreetly. Mouri.
请秘密的保护兰她们 拜托了 毛利
I've asked the inspector to look after Ran and the others.
兰她们我已经拜托警部他们了
Whether this will turn out for better or worse depends on us now.
这个到底是凶是吉那就要靠我们的脑子了啊
Speaking of which, did you learn anything?
说起来 你这边有什么收获吗
Yeah, it seems that on April 4th, an armored car was attacked on this carriage road.
嗯 好像4月4日在这个马车道上现金运钞车被袭击了
And the police said that Kaito Kiddo stole a diamond from the Miyama Art Museum on that day.
警察说这天也是怪盗基德从深山美术馆偷走钻石的日子
I see.
是吗
Anyway, I'll investigate on my own from here.
总之我这里我自己调查吧
Don't force yourself to do this, you kids.
小孩子就不用勉强了
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么
Maybe we're finished with the hint about the carriage road.
在马车道的提示也许到此为止了
What can we figure out with such little information?
只有这点信息能解开什么啊
But there are more hints.
可是 还有提示啊
Hints to solve the mystery.
解迷的提示
What?
什么
The hints I got were:
给我的提示是这样的
The cafe terrace at night and YOU CRY.
夜间的露天咖啡馆 YOU CRY 就是你在哭
So he gave you a different hint.
出了和我们不同的提示啊
I guess so.
就是这样啊
YOU CRY.
你在哭
Using the alphabet, it's Y-O-U-C-R-Y.
如果是英语字母的话Y-O-U-C-R-Y
Speaking of YOU...
说到YOU
Yes.
嗯
That's the initials of the marine university on the outskirts of Yokohama. Yokohama Ocean University.
在横滨郊外的横滨海洋大学 YOKOHAMA OCEAN UNIVERSITY
The rest of it is CRY.
剩下的是CRY啊
I have no idea about that part either.
这个我也不知道
Let's head over there.
去看看吧
To that place called YOU.
去那个YOU那里
Yeah.
是啊
Ran, hurry up!
兰 快点
Excuse me.
对不起
Yes, what do you need?
是 什么
What's with the red light on this ID blinking?
这个ID的红灯在忽亮忽灭是怎么回事
- Now we'll broadcast a message for a customer. - Well... What's this?
(现在播送客人的呼叫) 这个 什么啊
- Ran Mouri of Beika and her friend Kazuha... - I've never seen this thing before.
(从米花街来的毛利兰和同行的和叶) 我也是第一次看见
- Is that so?
是吗
Ran Mouri of Beika and her friend Kazuha...
(从米花街来的毛利兰和同行的和叶)
If you're there, please report to the medical station at once.
(如果在的话请火速赶到医务室去)
What's going on?
怎么回事
Could it be that something happened to the kids?
不会是孩子们出了什么事吧
If so, things must be serious.
那样的话不得了啊
Sorry, Sonoko.
对不起 园子
Can you go on alone?
你能一个人去吗
I'm okay.
可以啊
You should go quickly, if you're worried about those kids.
担心孩子们的话就快点去吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'll definitely eat as many as I want.
可以暴饮暴食了啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
She fainted in the park.
在园内倒下了
I think it's mild heatstroke.
我认为是轻度的中暑
Is it?
是吗
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay. Don't worry.
不要紧的 不要担心
But why did you call Kazuha as well?
可是为什么也叫了和叶呢
This is the first time I've spoken to this kid.
我和这孩子是第一次说话啊
Well...
这个
Isn't it obvious?
这个不是明摆着的吗
It's better to have two people around than only one.
两个人比一个人更安心啊
Right, right.
对的对的
She needs to get some rest.
稍微休息一会儿吧
Can you stay with her?
能陪着她吗
Of course.
当然
Please be by my side, always.
一直要在我身边哦
I thought she was just a cold kid.
我还认为是自大的孩子
Actually, she's quite cute, huh?
不是很可爱吗
It's so tiring to play this drama.
演这场戏 好累
CRY, CRY, CRY...
CRY CRY CRY
Maybe it's an abbreviation for some course?
课程名称的略称吗
Or extracurricular activity?
课外活动呢
Indeed.
是的啊
Aside from that...
别的可以考虑的东西
The crime research club of Yokohama. Crime Research of Yokohama.
横滨犯罪研究会 CRIME RESEARCH OF YOKOHAMA
I think that this club is infinitely close to the correct answer.
我认为这个社团和正解无限接近
You are...
你自己是？
I'm Saguru Hakuba.
我是白马探
In many ways, I am in the same position as you.
在很多意义上我是和你站在同一个立场上的人
You mean the same position?
你说同一个立场？
You're the son of the Police Chief and a high school detective, right?
是警视总长的儿子并且是高中生侦探吧
Yeah, although I failed to beat you, a schoolboy detective.
嗯 虽然输给了你这个小学生侦探啊
I see.
原来如此
So we have something in common, because my dad is the Osaka Police Chief.
和老爸是大阪府警察总部长的我是一样的啊
That's not all.
不只是这样啊
So, you are also...
这么说你也？
Someone important to me is also at Miracle Land.
对我重要的人也在MIRACLE LAND啊
Let's talk about it while walking.
闲话就边走边说
It's this CRY that's really wasting our time.
浪费时间才是CRY啊
Maybe that's because it will have us end up in tears.
会落得个哭的下场的
Yeah, that's right.
是的啊
Hello? Is anyone there?
喂 有人吗
Hello?
喂
We're coming in.
进来了哦
There are so many files!
了不起的资料啊
Hey, look at these pictures.
喂 看这个照片
They look like snaps from the research club members.
好像是研究会成员的照片啊
We should photograph these pictures.
这照片最好拍下来啊
Yeah.
是的啊
The client?
委托人
Yeah...
嗯
What?
什么
You surprised me, Heiji Hattori.
出乎意料啊 服部平次
I didn't expect you to find out those things with a simple "You Cry".
我没有想到只凭“YOU CRY”你能查到那里啊
Seriously, I'm shocked by you guys.
我被你们震惊了
Anyway, if you really want us to solve this case,
不管怎么都行 要是你希望我们解决事件的话
can't you give us some easier hints?
能不能再给我们更简单一点的提示呢
If it were that easy to solve, it'd be no fun for me.
要是被这么简单的解决掉了  我就不爽了
Besides...
而且
I'm testing your abilities as detectives,
我想考验一下你们作为侦探的本事
and whether or not you're qualified to solve my case.
以及有没有资格来解决我的事件
What are you talking about?
你说什么
There will be no more hints from here on out.
这里接下去就没有提示了
I'm looking forward to your performance,
我很期待哦
young detectives.
各位年轻的侦探们
Hey, wait!
喂 给我等一下
Damn it!
可恶
He hung up.
切断了
No hints?
没有提示吗
What are we going to do?
会变成怎样啊…
(Targets are at Yokohama Ocean University. Kill them all.)
(目标在横滨海洋大学 把他们干掉)
Who are you?
你们是？
What can I do for you?
有什么事吗
Well, we...
那个 我们…
We're planning to come to this university next year.
明年打算考这个大学
We're just looking around.
稍微做一下参观
If you do get in, please be sure to join our club.
那么考入的话一定要加入我们的社团哦
Yeah, of course.
当然了
Hey, miss.
大姐姐
Who are in the photos up there?
那里排列的照片是谁的照片
From the left are the photos of the club presidents in chronological order.
从左边开始是历代部长的照片哦
Then why is the photo of the third president taken down?
那么为什么第三任部长的照片被拿下来了呢
But, look!
可是 瞧啊
There are hooks up there beside the last photo.
最后一张照片的边上装着挂钩
Compared to the third photo,
比起第三张照片
we can see slightly lighter lines on the wall next to the next few photos, right?
后面几张照片的边上不是都有一点点没有被光照过的白色痕迹吗
This is because the third president's photo was taken down for some reason,
这个是因为某种原因第三任部长的照片被拿下来
and the next photos were all moved forward, right?
后面的照片按顺序错开再挂上的吧
Isn't that so?
不是吗
The third president Itou was expelled.
第三任的伊东被除名处分
Seems like his name was Jirou Itou.
好像是叫伊东次郎吧
No, his name was Tsuehiko Itou. Do you know him?
不是的 是叫伊东末彦 知道吗
Yeah, I guess so.
嗯 就算是吧
I think this is him, right?
好像是这个人吧
No.
不是的
It's this guy.
是这个人
Oh, I see.
啊 这样啊
What a good actor.
真会演戏
I'm sorry, I guess it's not the Itou I know.
对不起 好像和我认识的伊东不是同一个人啊
Tsuehiko Itou.
伊东末彦
Heiji, who's that? That Ito guy?
平次 那是谁啊 那个伊东什么的
If I knew, I wouldn't ask you to look it up for me.
就是不知道才拜托大泷帮我查的啊
Does the chief know?
本部长知道吗
It's confidential.
还是保密的
You said confidential, Heiji?
你说保密 平次啊
Then, I'll be waiting for your call.
那么我等着你的消息哦
Hey, Heiji!
喂 平次
Well, I'm going out for a smoke. Just a smoke...
那么 我去抽支烟 抽支烟
How about having something to eat at the school cafeteria?
怎么样 在学校食堂吃点什么吧
If my blood sugar drops, my thinking speed will slow down as well...
决斗的血倒流的话 总觉得大脑的转动有点…
Dummy. How can you have free time for that?
呆瓜 怎么有那种空闲啊
I'm still waiting for a call.
我在等电话啊
What's the use of a toothpick if you don't eat beef.
不吃牛肉要什么牙签啊
But people say, "it will be hard for a hungry person to win the fight."
可是也有空着肚子不好打仗这句话啊
Besides, I've already figured out what you're trying to figure out.
而且你要调查的东西已经知道了
The local Police Department is closer to Yokohama than the Osaka Police, huh?
警视厅比大阪府警察离横滨近啊
He's really annoying.
真让人火大啊
Yeah. Yes.
是 是的
Next time I get there, I'll take you out.
下次去你那里的时候我请你吃饭
Okay, please, Ao. Look it up for me quickly.
好 拜托了 小青 火速帮着查一下啊
What are you doing, Otaki?
你在干什么 大泷
Mr. Toyama!
远 远山
Were you on the phone with your cousin Aoki in the Kanagawa Police?
刚才的是在和神奈川县警察署的你的堂兄青木打电话吧
We haven't seen each other so long. I just wanted to hear his voice.
我是想听听好久不见的他的声音啊
Stop pretending.
不要隐藏了
It's a request from Heizou's son, isn't it?
是平藏他儿子的请求吧
I got his call as well.
我这里也接到电话了
What? He called you too?
什么嘛 远山那里也是啊
You've been fooled, Otaki.
上当了啊 大泷
Is there something wrong with my son?
我家的儿子怎么了
Chief!
本部长
Come to my office, and tell me everything about it.
能到我的房间好好说给我听听吗
It'll be better for you if you're honest.
老实交代的话会比较好哦
Well...
这个…
I gotta say this is really torture for me.
这个状态相当的痛苦啊
Then, it's up to you.
那么拜托了
Inspector Megure.
目暮警部
I'll go say hello.
我去打个招呼
Then, I'll come with you.
那样的话我也去
He's been taking care of Heiji for a long time.
平次一直受到他照顾的
Then, I want to go ride the Super Snake.
那么我想去乘SUPER SNAKE
The rest is up to you, thanks.
之后的拜托了
Wait a minute!
给我等等
You shouldn't get up yet!
不行 现在还不能起来
Stop him, please!
快阻止他 拜托
Understood.
嗯 明白
Inspector Megure!
目暮警部
Oh, Ran and Kazuha...
啊 兰还有和叶
What happened today?
今天怎么了
Why did you two come here together?
两个人一起过来
Is there something wrong?
有什么事件吗
It's nothing.
没什么
We're on break.
是休假
I'm here to play with Shiratori on break.
在休假和白鸟一起过来啊
Only you two came to Miracle Land?
只有两个人来MIRACLE LAND？
How rare...
真少见
Well, Ran...
那个 兰
Those kids.
那些孩子
Inspector.
警部
Hmm...
嗯
What? Seriously?
啊？ 真的假的啊
(The Super Snake is currently out of service due to a machinery inspection. We apologize for the inconvenience.)
（SUPER SNAKE因为在机器检修中 所以运行中止  给您添麻烦了）
This is your punishment for trying to sneak out.
想抢先被惩罚了吧
Let's go back to the medical station.
回到医务室去吧
I'm really sorry.
真的非常抱歉
For the sake of safety, please be understanding.
为了确保安全 拜托了
We'll begin giving out timed entry tickets now.
接下来会发放整理券
Robber!
强盗！
Robber! There's a robber!
强盗 有强盗
Ayumi!
步美
Ran!
兰
Ah? Why would Inspector Megure come here?
啊？ 目暮警部为什么在这里啊
Well, Takagi!
那个高木啊
What are you doing?
你在干什么
Nothing...
没什么 那个
Don't tell me you fell in love with some cute girl during our date?
不会是在约会的时候被可爱的女孩子迷花了眼吧
No... No way... That's impossible.
怎么可能有… 有 没有那样的事嘛
What?
什么嘛
What did you mean, exactly? I'm confused.
到底有还没有啊
Is that so?
是的啊
I'd better pretend I didn't see the inspector.
就当没有看见警部吧
Wow, this curry looks delicious.
哇 看起来很好吃的咖喱啊
I'm going to eat!
我开动了
Just eat up!
快吃吧
It's delicious! This curry...
好吃啊 这咖喱
This curry is disgusting!
难吃 这咖喱
It's all flour.
全是面粉
So, who is Tsuehiko Itou?
那么伊东末彦是怎么样的人呢
Itou is a wanted criminal who attacked an armored car on the April 4th of this year.
伊东是在今年的4月4日运钞车袭击事件中正在被通缉的犯人
I see.
原来如此
That's why his photo was taken down from the wall of that room.
所以照片被从课外活动室的墙上拿下来了
That's not all that's interesting about him.
颇有意思不仅仅是这个
Although he operated an investment advice firm after graduating,
他在大学毕业后虽然经营着投资顾问公司
at that firm, Far East Office, a murder took place.
在那个公司--FAR EAST OFFICE中也发生了杀人事件
What?
什么？
See? Interesting, huh?
怎么样？ 很有意思吧
Great! Let's go over and see!
好！ 快点去看看吧
That Far East Office.
那个FAR EAST OFFICE
I can't believe he ate it all...
居然全部吃完啦…
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome back, sir.
您回来啦 律师
Excuse me, Kuriyama. Can you get me a cold drink?
不好意思栗山 帮我来点冰的饮料吧
Sure.
是
This is Kisaki.
我是妃
Dear, what's wrong?
啊 老公 怎么了
Didn't you go to Miracle Land with Ran and the others today?
今天不是和小兰她们去Miracle Land了吗
Wait, you mean case files?
等等 你说事件的资料？
What are you doing?
你在做什么啊
Well... There is something.
这个… 有些事
About the shooting.
关于枪击事件
I see.
我知道了
About the armed robbery of the armored car on April 4th, right?
关于4月4日的持枪抢劫运钞车的事情吧
I'll look it up and call you back.
我马上查一下然后联系你
That would save me, then.
真是帮我大忙了
Dear?
老公？
Say, Eri.
我说英理
Do you think I can solve this case?
你觉得我能解决吗这个事件
To research, you gotta run, right? Former officer?
搜查是要靠跑的 不是这样吗 前警官大人
Yeah... Indeed. Then I'm counting on you for the files!
是… 是啊 资料就拜托了
Okay, I got it.
好 我知道了
Come here.
过来
Please come in.
请进
Sorry for the intrusion.
失礼了
Did someone call just now?
前面有人打电话过来吗
Yeah, I had a call.
嗯 有电话
From a real pain in the ass.
非常另人讨厌的家伙
Right, little Goro?
是吧 小"五郎"
So, it was from her husband.
是老公打来的啊
(Unauthorized personnel are not allowed to enter)
(无关人员禁止入内)
Although we're not allowed,
被禁止的话
I still think I gotta take a look inside.
还是想进去看一下
All detectives would think so.
是侦探的都这样想
The murder victim was Nishio Masaharu, the Sales Director at Far East Office.
被杀的是西尾正治是FAR EAST OFFICE的销售部长
It seems that he was killed by a sniper.
好像是被狙击枪所杀
At college, he was a classmate of the Club President Itou.
和社长伊东是大学时代的同学
In other words...
也就是说
Nishio was also a member of that crime research club.
西尾也是犯罪研究会的吧
That's right.
的确
Come and look here.
过来看
Come and look here? Hey, isn't this my phone? When did you...
什么过来看 喂 这不是我的手机吗 什么时候
Look.
看
The front row of the picture. In the middle is the club president, Tsuehiko Itou.
照片里面的前面那排 在中间的是当时的部长伊东末彦
On his right is the one who was murdered, Nishio.
右边就是被杀的西尾
So, who is the woman on Itou's left?
那么 伊东左边的女人是
This woman is Reiko Shimizu.
这个女人叫清水丽子
She seemed to work for the same company.
她好像也在那个公司工作
She committed suicide on May 15th.
5月15日自杀了
Suicide?
自杀？
It was during the time that she was investigated and questioned by the police.
就在遭受警方调查和逼问期间
About the shooting case of Nishio?
是指枪杀西尾的事情吗
The investigation and pursuit pushed her too far.
调查和追踪都逼得非常紧
This is where the shooting incident happened.
这里就是狙击事件的现场
Although everything's covered in dust,
虽然已经积了些灰了
things are still the same as that day of the incident.
似乎还是维持着事件当日的状态啊
But I think the blinds and windows were open at that time.
不过当时好像百叶窗和窗门都开着吧
The culprit shot from the toilet of that building, right?
犯人就是在那幢楼的厕所里开枪的吧
The gun he used was a Charter Arms AR- 7 with a sniper scope and silencer attachments.
用的枪是CHARTER ARMS ZR SEVEN　带狙击镜及消音器
Eight empty casings fell into the toilet where the culprit was.
八发子弹的弹壳都掉在了犯人所在的厕所里
The culprit shot all eight bullets.
犯人把总数八颗子弹全数射出
One of the bullets hit Nishio in the back of the head.
其中一发击中了西尾的后脑
I guess he was killed instantly.
估计是当场死亡
Afterwards, there was a plan written by Itou found on Nishio's desk. The plan was about their attack on the armored car.
之后发现了在西尾桌上  由伊东写的袭击运钞车的计划
Therefore, Itou, who was still alive then, was placed on the wanted list.
于是尚且存活的伊东便遭到了警方的通缉
Then why would Reiko Shimizu be investigated?
那清水丽子为什么会被调查呢
I don't know that much.
那我还没知道的这么详细
See, Hattori, if he was really shot in the back of the head,
看啊 服部 如果后脑被击中的话
don't you think there was too little blood?
你不觉得出血太少了吗
Yeah, but we have a large pool of blood over here.
是啊 反而这边倒是留下了一大滩血渍呢
What exactly happened?
到底是怎么回事
And the blood on the back of the seat was flowing straight down to the cushion.
椅子靠背上的血迹却又是笔直地淌到了坐垫上
Look at this.
还有这里快看
One of the casters was shot and fell off.
底座的一个小轮子被打穿掉了下来
I see. That's how it happened.
原来如此 是这样啊
Yeah, that's it.
就是这么回事呢
This is Hattori.
我是服部
You've made it to the next round, Hattori.
你已经进行到下一环节了呢 服部
Yeah, finally...
啊 总算
I think you've figured out what case you're supposed to solve.
相信让你们解决的事件已经明白了吧
The shooting case of Masaharu Nishio, right?
枪杀西尾正治的事件吧
Hey, could you be...
喂 莫非你就是…
Damn it!
可恶
What?
什么？
Bike?
机车
Anyway, it's definitely not something good, huh?
不过肯定不是向好的方面发展的吧
Who are those guys?
那些家伙是什么人啊
I guess they are NPCs who make the game more interesting
估计是让游戏变得更有趣的家伙吧
That's what the client said.
委托人是这么说的
It's a little too interesting.
太有趣了
This is not good. Let's split up.
这样下去可不妙 分头行动
Okay. Got it.
好 知道了
Okay, one on one, huh?
好 单挑是吧
Just come at me.
尽管放马过来吧
What an ugly face.
这脸还真是丑啊
Ah? Did I hurt your feeling?
啊 很在意啊
Damn...
可恶
You're so tricky! Drop the gun and fight, if you have the guts!
好卑鄙啊 有种枪扔掉肉搏
I wonder if Kudo can get away.
工藤这家伙不知道能不能顺利逃脱
Geez. My T-shirt was stained with the paint. It's useless now.
真受不了 油漆都撒在T恤上了 这衣服没用了
A man in a baseball cap and a jacket, right?
是戴棒球帽穿夹克的男人干的吧
But he's probably already run away, right?
不过大概已经逃出去了吧
You have a point.
说的也是哦
What's wrong?
怎么了
Don't you think he's suspicious?
你不觉得很可疑吗那个人
The one in the yellow T-shirt?
那个穿黄颜色T恤的？
Look, his hair has layered out.
你看 头发变成了两段
That means he was wearing a hat.
就是说他戴过帽子
He probably got rid of the jacket and the bag he stole.
嗯 说不定已经把夹克和抢来的包一起处理掉了
As expected of the top-notch high school student detective in Kanto, Shinichi Kudo's girlfriend.
不愧是关东第一高中生侦探工藤新一的女友
To be exact, I'm not his girlfriend.
也不是什么女友啦
Coke was spilled on the culprit's shoes, right?
可乐确实洒在犯人的鞋子上了吧
Yes, that was my plan to leave evidence.
对 为了留下证据我是故意的
Oh, my bag!
啊 我的包
You're amazing, Genta!
好厉害啊 元太
That's not true, Ayumi.
不是这样的 步美
You shouldn't brag, Genta.
吹牛可是不行的哦 元太
Help!
来人啊
I've seen it all!
我都看在眼里哦
Ah? is that so?
啊 是那样的吗
It's him!
是他
It's an old lady.
是位阿姨啊
Hey, Ayumi.
喂 步美
You sure it's him, Ayumi?
就是他吗 步美
Yes, his left sneaker has Cola spilled on it.
嗯 左脚的运动鞋上沾着可乐的污渍
Look at him, he's looking around.
你看他正左顾右盼呢
He looks really suspicious.
怎么看都很可疑呢
We can't be wrong.
不会错的吧
Let's follow him.
跟着他吧
That's not good. Where did they all go? Those kids!
这下不妙 都去哪里了呢 那些孩子
Thief! Stop!
小偷 站住
We won't let you run away!
别想逃
Get out ! Get out of my way!
让开 别挡路
Get out of my way!
让开让开
Out of my way!
别挡路
We're borrowing this!
借我用一下
Stop right there!
给我站住
Just give up.
死心吧
The security guards will be here soon.
马上警卫就过来了
Don't stick your nose into other's business!
别多管闲事
Oh, no!
啊 糟了
Ayumi!
步美
Don't move! Or I can't guarantee what will happen to this kid!
别动 乱来的话我可不保证这个小鬼会怎么样
Number 5 is approaching the gate.
5号正接近大门
Who is it?
是谁啊
Number 5, Ayumi Yoshida.
5号 吉田步美
Is that so?
是吗
Don't come any closer!
都不要过来
If you come any closer, this kid will die.
过来的话小鬼的命就不保了哦
Hey, let that kid go!
喂 你快吧放了那孩子
I'll be your hostage instead.
换我来做人质好了
Don't be ridiculous, old man!
别开玩笑了老头
Then, let me...
那 换我…
I'll be the hostage.
我来做人质
It's because of me that she got caught.
都是因为我那孩子才会被他抓住的
You can't go there.
你们不能过去
I mean, how can we possibly let civilians like you be hostages?
不是的 怎么能让你们这样的百姓去做替身呢？
Cut the crap!
不要乱讲话
I won't change hostages!
我绝对不会换人质的
You guys, don't move until I get out of this gate.
你们这些家伙 我从这门出去之前都不许动
After all, this kid's life is at stake.
可是关系到这小鬼的性命哦
That's bad, if they just get out like this...
糟了 如果就这么出去的话
Say, this is the entrance.
我说 这里可是入口
The exit is next door.
出口在旁边
Stop nagging! Get out of my way!
别喽嗦 快滚开
It's useless to yell at me.
你骂人也没用
Rules are rules.
规矩是规矩
Honestly, you are not a kid or something.
真是的 年纪也不小了
Why don't you know how to follow the rules?
这点规矩都遵守不了
Go arrest him!
你觉悟吧
Get out of the way!
让开
There are hostages everywhere.
人质可是到处都有的
Stay back
别过来
One step closer and this woman will...
过来一步 这个女人就
What will you do?
你想怎么样
Huh? What will I do?
咦 "想怎么样"？
Can you tell me?
能告诉我吗
Excuse me... Can you let me through...
不好意思 让… 让一让好吗
Sorry, I finally got the ice cream.
啊 对不起 我买蛋筒来了
Miss Sato.
佐藤小姐
Inspector Megure?
目暮警官
Well... What are you all doing here?
那个… 你们都这里做什么呢
That's what I wanted to ask you.
这是我要问你的话
(Ah, no... Actually...)
(啊不… 那个… )
Kudo...
工藤
Kudo! Kudo!
工藤 工藤
Hey, Kudo!
喂 工藤
Kudo!
工藤
You're finally awake!
你终于醒了啊
Where am I...
这儿是
You're in Mr. Agasa's car.
阿笠大伯的车里面
Professor?
博士？
Don't move.
别乱来哦
I've given you first aid treatment, but there's a possibility that you'll have a fractured bone.
虽然已经帮你紧急处理了 但有骨裂的可能
Hattori, did you...
服部 是你把我…
No, it was Hakuba...
不是的 是白马
He called Mr. Agasa here. When Mr. Agasa arrived, he saw Hakuba holding you in his arms.
阿笠大伯被他叫来 看见满身伤痕的你已经被抱上来了
Then, Mr. Agasa called me, so here we are.
我也是被大伯叫来会合的
Hakuba...
白马他
He said he had something to investigate, then let me carry you into the car and left.
他说还有事情要查 让我把你抱进车里 自己走了
What time is it now? How long has it been since I fell into the river?
现在几点了 我掉进河里到现在多久了
It's been two hours. It's now 8:30 at night.
过了2个小时 现在已经晚上8点半了
Only an hour hand a half left.
只剩下1个半小时了啊
Anyway, we're now going to the Red Castle.
总之现在就往RED CASTLE方向去
You've already known the culprit who shot Nishio?
你已经知道了吗 射杀西尾的犯人
Not yet, we're just going there.
还没有 就是往那去而已
After all, there is no use staying around here.
待着也不是办法
Oh right. When you were asleep, Officer Otaki called me back.
对了 你睡着的时候大泷警官来过电话了
He told me a lot of things.
从中知道了很多事情哦
There's something else related to the shooting case of Nishio.
在西尾被射杀的事件里还有些别的细节啊
On the night Nishio was shot...
西尾被射杀的那天晚上
A car flipped near the containers at the docks. It was badly damaged.
一辆轿车在集装箱码头翻车  车辆严重损毁
The driver was Tsuehiko Itou.
开车的就是伊东末彦
It is said that he was critically wounded. It was a miracle that he could survive.
据说伤势严重能活下来已经是奇迹了
He stayed in the intensive care unit for a whole month.
整整一个月都没能从集中治疗病房出来过
The police investigated the car that was involved in the accident.
警方调查了事故发生的车辆
They found the hydraulic pipes were tampered with.
发现车子用紧紧绑住的管子恶意改装过
And also, they found a sniper rifle with a silencer in the trunk.
而且在后备箱中发现了带消音器的狙击枪
Although the fingerprints had been wiped...
虽然指纹都已经被擦掉了
it was confirmed that sniper rifle was the one used to kill Nishio.
但可以肯定就是射杀西尾的那把狙击枪
So did they arrest Itou?
那么伊东被捕了吗
No. Two months after the accident, the police were finally allowed to visit the patient.
不 事故发生2个月后 警方终于得到了会见许可
When the police went in...
警察进去一看
We're coming in.
进来喽
Itou was no longer in the ward.
伊东竟然已经不在病房里了
After that, the police couldn't find any trace of Itou, so they placed him on the wanted list.
之后伊东便失去了踪迹遭到了通缉
And he was suspected of robbery during the time he was still in the hospital.
并被怀疑在住院期间有抢劫的罪行
So, this Itou is the culprit, right?
那么 这个叫伊东就是犯人喽
Yeah, there's no doubt that Itou shot Nishio.
啊 没错确实是伊东向西尾开枪
Itou's footprints were also found at the sniper's position.
狙击现场也留下了伊东的大量脚印
There were gunshot residues on his clothes.
衣服上出现有硝烟反应
Those eight shell casings at the scene could be loaded in the magazine at once.
现场采集的弹壳也正好是弹匣所能容纳的全部8颗
And all of the rifle marks match, but...
而且弹道也都完全吻合 但是…
Mascara?
睫毛膏？
We found traces of mascara on the rifle's sniper scope.
枪的狙击镜上附着极少量的睫毛膏
That's it.
就是这个
That means it came from whoever looked through the scope, right?
也就是说是用狙击镜瞄准的时候沾上的吧
That's right.
正是如此
Speaking of this mascara,
说到这睫毛膏
they looked into the women around Itou and Nishio,
调查了下伊东和西尾周围的女性当中
and found one woman who used this mascara.
有一人是使用这种睫毛膏的
It was Reiko Shimizu.
就是这位清水丽子
Ah, the one who committed suicide after the incident?
啊 就是事件之后自杀的那个
A Madonna of the Crime Research of Yokohama Club.
横滨海洋大犯罪研究会中麦当娜式的人物
She was very close to both the murdered Nishio and the missing Itou.
据说和被杀的西尾和失踪的伊东关系特别亲密
After graduation, she joined Itou's company with Nishio
毕业后和西尾一起进入伊东的公司
as the manager of their data room.
是资料室的主管
Nishio and Itou were the ones who attacked the armored car, right?
袭击运钞车的就是西尾和伊东吧
Itou may have had a motive to kill Nishio.
伊东是可能有动机杀西尾的
Could Reiko Shimizu have had any motive?
清水丽子有什么动机吗
According to the her colleagues at the company, Nishio had been pestering her. She hated him very much.
据公司的同事说 一直遭到西尾的纠缠 非常厌恶
The police pressed her about the mascara on the scope
警方以狙击镜上沾有睫毛膏
and the inconsistencies in her alibi for the night of Nishio's murder.
而造成事件当日的不在证明不能成立为由逼问了清水
But she didn't say anything.
她却守口如瓶
And then, on May 15h...
然后5月15日
She jumped.
跳下去了
Although Reiko Shimizu's body wasn't found,
虽然没有找到清水丽子的尸体
due to the fierce currents, the police determined that she had no chance of survival.
由于乱流是不可能得救的 警方如此判断
Itou disappeared from the hospital eight days later.
伊东从医院失踪是事后第8天
The two suspects in Nishio's murder case both disappeared.
结果杀死西尾的嫌疑犯双双失踪
Without any trace of suspects, the investigation of this case had to stop.
事件的调查由于无法找到嫌疑犯而告一段落
Of course, without its president, Itou's company went bankrupt.
当然没有社长伊东的公司也宣告倒闭
The company that bought it out was Miyama Corporation.
将之收购的就是深山商事
Is it related to the Miyama Art Museum?
和深山美术馆也有关系吗
The one where Kiddo went to steal the jewel?
基德去偷宝石的那个
That's right.
说对了
The president, Souichirou Miyama, was also a member of Itou's crime research club.
社长深山总一郎也是和伊东他们一个犯罪研究会的
He was four years Itou's senior.
长他们四岁的学长
Itou also had been very concerned about Miyama.
伊东也一直对深山虎视眈眈
Ah, speaking of Kiddo...
啊 关于基德
Mr. Otaki told me something interesting about him.
大泷叔叔顺便告诉了我件有趣的事情
On April 4th, after stealing the jewel from Miyama Art Museum,
4月4日 前去深山美术馆偷东西的基德
Kiddo ran into a group of burglars on the run after robbing the armored car.
和逃亡中的袭击运钞车的犯人正好撞上
It is said that someone heard gunshots there.
据说从那里传出了枪击的声音
Gunshots?
枪声？
Since Kiddo never uses guns,
基德从不使用枪这一点来看
it must have been the burglars shooting at him.
是强盗单方面向基德开枪的吧
I'm afraid the reason why they shot him is because...
开枪的原因恐怕  就是
Kiddo saw their faces, right?
被基德看到了脸孔 对吧
Yeah, Government and Charter Arms ammunition was found at the scene.
啊 在现场发现了GOVERMENT和CHARTER ARMS的弹匣
From then on, every time Kiddo went to steal something, there was someone trying to kill him.
从那以后每当基德前去偷东西的时候都有人要取他性命
See? Interesting, huh?
怎么样 有意思吧
But it's still not enough to deduce who killed Nishio.
不过就凭这点还是无法推断杀西尾的犯人啊
Indeed. I guess we didn't find the most important part yet.
是啊 确实如果还有一点知道了就好了
Speaking of which, Mouri just called and talked about an important witness he found.
说起来 刚才毛利打过电话来说找到了重要的证人
The day Nishio was killed,
西尾被杀那天
it seems that a janitor heard a few metallic sounds coming from the toilet.
好像有清洁工听到从那个厕所里传出几下金属物的掉落声
Then, he saw Itou running out of the toilet with a golf bag in his arms.
然后看到伊东抱着高尔夫球包从厕所里跑了出来
Then the metallic sounds must be the sound of shell casings falling onto the floor.
恐怕金属物的声音就是弹壳掉在地上的声音
And inside that golf bag must be a Charter Arms AR-7.
高尔夫球包里装的就是CHARTER ARMS ZR SEVEN吧
Now things are clear, Mr. Agasa.
这样就清楚了阿笠大伯
Where is Mr. Mouri?
大叔呢
He said that he had solved the case, so he went to the client first.
他说案件解开了所以先去委托人那儿了
So, did Mr. Mouri...
难道说 大叔他
That's terrible!
糟了 那不得了
Is that so?
是吗
Don't stop, Mr. Agasa! Go full speed!
不要停 大伯 全速前进
Got it.
我知道了
I knew you'd come, Kaito Kiddo.
我知道你会来的怪盗基德
You set things in place on the roof during the day,
白天在屋顶做好手脚
and now finally came in from there.
现在终于从那儿进来了啊
I will not let you take the jewel.
我是不会让你把宝石拿走的
I won't take the jewel unless I make an announcement first.
我若是不做予告的话是不会拿宝石的
What?
什么
I came here tonight bid you farewell.
今晚我是来和你道别的
I don't want to put my life on the line any longer.
我不想再过一直有人要取我性命的日子了
As expected of Kaito Kiddo. You've figure it out, huh?
果然是怪盗基德 已经都看透了吗
Yeah, kind of.
嗯 稍微
But there's something I still don't understand.
但是有些事我还不明白
I have sent you back the diamond I stole,
偷走的钻石我应该又寄回给你了
but there are still someone trying to kill me.
却还是有人要来杀我
I finally understood the reason.
其中的理由我终于懂了
You're very protective of your junior schoolmates, huh?
你很爱护自己的学弟学妹呢
You shouldn't witness my cute juniors' game. It was your fault.
居然看到了我可爱的学弟学妹的游戏 那就是你不对了
A guard died for it, and you call it a game?
杀死了一个警卫 居然还说是游戏
Accidents always happen in games.
游戏和意外是同时存在的
But unfortunately, you saw them both.
可是不巧都被你看见了
I couldn't do nothing when one of my cute juniors asked me for help, right?
可爱的学弟学妹向我寻求帮助 我总不能坐视不管吧
What... what are you doing?
你… 你这是什么动作
Did you really think I would just come over here without any preparation?
你真的认为我会什么准备都不做就乖乖地过来吗
Do it! Shoot him!
做了他 开枪杀了他
What... What is this?
这… 这是什么啊
Don't be scared. It's just sleeping gas.
不用怕 只是催眠瓦斯而已
Didn't you notice? I've broken in here several times since last time I came in on April 4th.
你没发觉吗 我4月4日进来之后 又入侵好几次了
What?
什么
And the reason I set up on the roof in broad daylight...
而且今天白天光明正大的上楼顶做的手脚
was that I wanted to let you know I would come tonight
就是为了让你知道我今晚要来
and ensure you would appear here with your hired killers.
然后引出你和你雇的杀手们
How can that be?
怎么可能
If you have anything to say, say it to the police I called here.
要辩解就跟我叫来的警察说吧
Don't forget your lovely junior who's sleeping behind this curtain.
与在这个窗帘后熟睡的你那可爱的学妹一起哦
So, where has that "junior" gone?
"学妹"不知上哪去了
I believe those two also have something to share.
那里的两位也会说出许多事情吧
Something about this museum full of stolen items.
关于这个满是赃物的美术馆的故事
It's Kidd! Kiddo is up there!
是基德 基德出现了
I guess this is the end of your game,
你的游戏也该到此结束了
and it's in the worst possible way. Self-destruct.
而且是以最差的自摆乌龙的方式
Open the door! Police! Open the door!
快开门 是警察 开门
Wait for me, Ran
你等着我 小兰
Thank you for your work, Detective Mouri.
你辛苦了 毛利侦探
The client is getting tired of waiting for you.
委托人已经等得不耐烦了
Please.
请
Detective Mouri has come back.
毛利侦探已经回来了
Sorry, I know you're tired, but there's not much time left.
对不起 我知道您已经很累了 不过也没有时间了
Proceed with your report.
请赶快报告一下吧
The case you asked me to investigate
你想要调查的事件
is an attack on the armored car on April 4th this year,
是今年4月4日在马车道发生的袭击运钞车事件
and the truth about the related shooting case of Masaharu Nishio.
以及与此相关联的西尾正治遭射杀的真相
I'll go to meet the kids at Miracle Land.
我到MIRACLE LAND去找孩子们
Okay.
好
Take care of Kazuha for me.
和叶也拜托了
Got it.
我知道了
The two men who attacked the armored car on the carriage road were Tsuehiko Itou and Masaharu Nishio.
在马车道袭击运钞车的是伊东末彦与西尾正治两人
But Nishio shot the guard who was trying to resist.
但是西尾枪杀了正要做抵抗的警卫
Four days later, Nishio was killed by someone unknown.
4天后 这次换成西尾不知道被谁杀害了
The police suspected that the murderer was Reiko Shimizu,
警方怀疑是就在西尾身边的
a co-worker who was close to Nishio.
在一个公司工作的清水丽子所为
But I don't think so.
不过我不这么认为
The murder's motive was...
犯人的动机是
he had a perfect plan, but Nishio meddled this plan.
自己一手制定的完美计划中却出现了西尾的背叛
Right, the murderer who killed Masaharu Nishio is...
对 杀害西尾正治的犯人就是
Wait a minute!
等一下
You two?
你… 你们
You two, Detective Mouri is now reporting...
你们… 现在毛利侦探正在报告…
Oh, no!
糟了
Hey, what's wrong? Are you all right?
喂 你怎么了 没事吧
Detective Mouri, please continue to report.
毛利侦探 你赶快继续
Like I was saying, the murderer who killed Nishio was... Ouch...
所以我说了啊 杀害西尾的犯人就是 痛…
Sorry about that, Mr. Mouri.
对不起了 大叔
Not good! The monitor is off!
糟了 显示屏关了
Damn it!
可恶
Damn, which button is it?
可恶 开关到底是哪个按钮
What's that?
那… 那是什么
Could it be that... the client is inside?
莫非… 委托人可能就在里面
What?
什么
When I was on the phone with this Takada earlier,
刚才和这个叫高田打电话的时候
I heard the same noise as when I was on the phone with the client.
我好像听到了和与委托人打电话时一样的噪音
I see.
原来如此
We don't have much time. Let's go.
没时间了 走吧
It's so dark.
真是漆黑啊
I have no choice. Let's go.
顾不上这么多了 走吧
Welcome, Shinichi Kudo, Heiji Hattori.
欢迎你来 工藤新一 服部平次
Finally, we meet.
啊 终于见到你了
Far East Office President, Mr. Tsuehiko Itou.
FAR EAST OFFICE 社长伊东末彦先生
You two live up to your names.
果然名不虚传
I knew it was the right decision to put you two together.
果然把你们组合在一起是个正确的决定
Yeah, you could say that.
可以这么说吧
I'm sorry I can only meet you guys in this way.
我这身样子对你们失礼了
It's because of my handicap.
因为已经成了残废
From the accident at the pier, right?
码头的事故吧
Yeah, I know I will never recover.
是啊 我知道自己身体已经不可能复原了
That's why I shut myself up in here.
所以一直待在这里
All these hidden assets of mine were invested by one of my friends.
背后的资产也都是拜托朋友来投资而获得的
Including Miracle Land.
MIRACLE LAND也是如此
It's Mr. Souichirou Miyama, right?
深山总一郎先生是吧
Impressive.
太棒了
You figured out even this thing?
连这你都知道了吗
We can give you our report, but there's not much time left.
报告是可以 不过已经没有时间了
Have you found out the truth for me?
真相你们都帮我找出来了吗
Yes.
嗯
My days are numbered.
我也活不长了
That's why I need a detective to find out the truth for me.
所以需要侦探来帮我解开真相
A real detective who has not just brains, but the toughness.
不仅有头脑 不屈不挠的真正的名侦探
Alright, tell me the truth you've found.
好 快告诉我吧 你们找的真相
April 8th,
4月8日
at the office of Far East Office, Masaharu Nishio was killed.
在FAR EAST OFFICE办公室的 西尾正治
The culprit who shot him from the toilet of the adjacent building was
从对面大楼的厕所里将其射杀的犯人的名字是
Reiko Shimizu.
清水丽子
She made you out to be the murderer in Nishio's murder.
他将杀死西尾的罪行嫁祸到你头上
And, she also planned that accident to kill you.
而你那起事故也是她想将你抹杀而一手策划好的
You're lying!
你骗人
It was me who shot Nishio from the toilet.
是我在厕所里开枪打西尾的
So you're the same as the police?
你们原来和警察是一样的吗
You're as useless as they are?
如此无能吗
It's true that you used a sniper rifle in that toilet.
确实你在厕所里使用了狙击枪
But it was after Reiko Shimizu shot him.
不过是在清水丽子开枪之后
What?
什么
You two missed.
你们时间错开了
- The 7 rounds you fired... - Missed?
你所射出的7发子弹
7 rounds?
你说7发？
That sniper rifle's magazine should hold 8 rounds.
那把狙击枪应该能装8发子弹
You panicked and ran away without cleaning up the shell castings on the floor.
慌慌张张连掉在地上的弹壳都不收拾就逃跑的你
I guess you couldn't even remember how many shots you fired.
自己到底开了几枪估计也不记得了吧
By that time, Nishio had already been killed.
那个时候其实西尾已经被杀害了
How come?
怎么可能
I saw it all. Nishio fell to the floor after one of my shots.
我都看到的 西尾是中了我射出的子弹再倒在地上
Acually, one of the shot happened to blow a caster off his chair.
你射出的某颗子弹只是刚好射坏了椅子的轮子上而已
Then isn't it possible that one of my shots happened to hit Nishio?
那我的子弹就没可能正好打到西尾吗
Are you idiot? Who would sit around so calmly while his room was shot up?
白痴啊你吗 谁会被子弹乱射还这么镇定地坐在椅子上不动啊
Then, maybe my first shot happened to hit...
那最初的那一发正好打到…
The blood on the back of the chair that Nishio was sitting on that day
西尾死亡当日所坐的椅子靠背上的血迹
had obviously flowed straight down before drying.
明显是笔直淌下来的状态然后凝固的
That's how we figured it out.
所以这样就明白了
There was a sniper who shot Nishio's head with one single shot,
一枪射中西尾头部的狙击手
And there was also an amateur who shot around the room after the blood had dried.
和血液凝固之后乱射一通的菜鸟两个犯人这件事
Although we couldn't tell which one was the true sniper,
虽然由此还不能推定哪个是真正的狙击手
after listening to the testimony of Mr. Mouri's witness,
听了毛利大叔所找到的证人的话之后
things became clear.
就一清二楚了
That is, he heard the several metallic sounds from the toilet,
也就是关于厕所里传出数声金属物掉落的声音
and saw you hurriedly running out with a golf bag.
以及你抱着高尔夫包慌慌张张跑出来的证词
The metallic sounds were the shell casings falling on the tiled floor.
金属物的声音就是弹壳掉在瓷砖上的声音
There were several sounds, which means that amateur was you.
传出了几次 说明乱射的就是你
In other words, the true sniper was Reiko Shimizu.
也就是说狙击手是清水丽子
And one who shot his chair at random
而乱射一通将椅子射翻
and changed the crime scene by making the victim fall on the floor was you.
让案发现场变成死者躺在地上的状态的是你
Inside the golf bag was a Charter Arms AR- 7.
高尔夫包里面就是CHARTER ARMS ZR SEVEN
Before you shot, Reiko gave you that bag, didn't she?
你开枪之前丽子将这个包交给了你 对不对
That's true.
确实如此
But how can you be so sure that it was Reiko who shot him?
但为什么说丽子她开了枪
Because on the sniper scope,
因为狙击镜上留下了
there were traces of a mascara, which was always used by Reiko Shimizu.
清水丽子平时一直使用的睫毛膏
How is it possible?
怎么可能
After you got the bag from her and shot all the bullets from the toilet,
从她手上拿到包在厕所将子弹全数射完之后
you drove to the pier to dispose of the rifle and the car,
想把枪和车一并处理掉所以前往码头
I guess the part of your car out of order were the brakes, right?
我想你车上出问题的应该是刹车吧
her motive probably was to keep the money from the armored car robbery all to herself.
动机应该是想将独吞从运钞车抢来的钱
She was there when your attacked the armored car, right?
她当时也在吧 袭击运钞车的时候
But when you were on the run, you run into Kaito Kiddo.
不料逃走途中与怪盗基德相遇
Kiddo saw your faces, so you decided to kill him.
被基德看到脸的你们为了封住基德的嘴巴
But instead, you were trapped in a zigzag road, so, in a panic, you shot Kiddo.
反而被引入弯弯曲曲的小道 一慌张就向基德开了枪
Don't forget the Government and sniper rifle shell castings were left on the road.
GOVERMENT手枪和狙击枪的弹壳可是都留在路上了哟
No matter how well a person can drive,
不管是怎么驾驶技术出众的家伙
it's impossible to drive in such a zigzag road with one hand
都不可能一边单手在弯弯曲曲的小道开车
while using the other hand to shoot Kiddo flying in the sky.
一边瞄准在天空飞翔的基德开枪的
That is to say,
也就是说
there were two more with you,
除了你之外还有两个人
who were holding the sniper rifle and the Government.
拿着狙击枪和GOVERMENT手枪的人
So, Masaharu Nishio and Reiko Shimizu were also sitting in the car.
西尾正治和清水丽子也坐在车上
We heard most of the evidence from the police.
关于这个推理的证据大多数都是从警察那里听来的
Because the witness that Mr. Mouri found was also found by the police.
因为毛利大叔找到的证人 如果去找警察的话也可以更快的找到
The police knew this information,
警察知道这个真相
so they put their attention on Reiko.
所以就想把注意力放在丽子身上了
That's right.
是的
Even from the beginning, this case didn't need a great police officer, nor a great detective.
这个事件从一开始就不需要名警察和名侦探
The mystery has been solved.
谜解开了
Please release Ran and the others' IDs.
请解开兰他们的ID
Liar. Reiko wouldn't do that.
骗人 丽子做了那样的事
Liar. Liar. Liar!
骗人 骗人 骗人
They're not liars.
不是骗人的哦
As expected, you're still alive.
果然还是活着啊
Reiko? Are you Reiko?
丽子 是丽子吗
I gotta say, as my partner, you're really unreliable.
你的话作为我的搭档靠不住啊
So was Nishio.
而且西尾也是
He was too violent.
他只懂暴力
If I let him be alive any longer, I would've been in danger.
活的时间一长我不是很危险吗
Itou, you're too cautious.
伊东太过小心了
And you always tried to show off when we talked.
而且说话都是说大话的
It is not fun to be with you.
在一起的话没有乐趣啊
I know you hired that many detectives, trying to take all the blame for me...
虽然据说集中了侦探要替我承担罪过让我活下去
But that ends today.
可是这也在今天结束了
Those assets handled by Miyama will all be mine.
深山管理的你的财产就归我使用了
You mean Miyama?
你说深山
Miyama met his end as well.
深山也完蛋了
He was finished by Kaito Kiddo.
被怪盗基德干掉了
After all of this, the one who survived will be me.
最终活下来的是我
Wait a minute!
等等
Kudo!
工藤
Don't move.
别动
That's a Walther PPK.
那是华尔沙PPK
8 bullets in total.
子弹是8颗
When she runs out of ammunition, we'll end this.
全部打完的话就能做个了断了
6, 7, 8.
6 7 8
Now!
就是现在
Hattori.
服部
Sorry.
抱歉啊
I'm ambidextrous.
我可是双手都好使啊
Grab it, Kudo!
抓住 工藤
In the air, you don't need your feet to support your body, right?
在空中的话就不用支撑脚了
Right.
是啊
Reiko? Reiko, what's wrong?
丽子 丽子怎么了
What happened, Reiko?
怎么了 丽子
Reiko!
丽子
Please release the IDs.
请解开ID
They can be released, right?
可以解开的吧
Yes, thank you. Please send an ambulance now.
是的 拜托了 火速叫辆救护车来
What?
什么
What's wrong?
怎么了
Error?
ERROR？
She made things worse.
真是越搞越麻烦了
Hey, Kudo, do you know how to fix it?
喂 工藤 你知道怎么弄吗
It can't all be broken.
不可能全部都坏了
We must find the working parts.
只有寻找还能用的部分
I guess this is it for me.
我已经完蛋了吗
Kudo.
工藤
Your voice sounds like a child's.
听你的声音有点孩子气啊
Hattori, is there still an error?
服部 还是ERROR状态吗
Yeah, it didn't change.
嗯 没有改变
So it really is set to a timed explosion!
果然设定了时间爆炸
What's that?
那是什么
It's exactly 10:00.
正好是10点
Damn...
可恶
Which one should I click?
按哪个才好呢
I want to ride the Super Snake...
好想乘啊 SUPER SNAKE
It's been under maintenance.
一直是故障状态啊
But my dessert is late.
可是好慢啊 我的甜点
Stop complaining.
不要发牢骚
This is all on inspector.
这都是警部的请客啊
Don't get fat, Inspector Megure.
不要变胖哦 目暮警部
He's already fat enough.
就像你看到的那样
Really?
真的啊？
Well, Inspector Megure...
那个 目暮警部
Is there anything wrong?
发生了什么吗
Why do you ask?
什么啊？
Because the police officers are all gathering here.
因为警察们都聚集在一起
Nothing.
没什么
Inspector Megure.
目暮警部
Oh, Shiratori!
哦 白鸟
Excuse me, Ran.
抱歉 兰
How is it?
怎么了
The customers and the hotel staff have all been evacuated.
这周围的客人和饭店的员工都已经让他们离开了
The only ones here are those kids and us police.
在这里的只有那些孩子和我们警察
I see.
是吗
What are you doing, Shinichi?
你在干什么 新一
Damn!
可恶
Sharing secrets will make a man and a woman become closer.
由于共享秘密男人和女人间的关系变深
The deepest secret is to commit a crime with the woman you love.
最深的秘密是和爱着的女性一起犯罪啊
See? That attack on the armored car showed my love for Reiko.
所以袭击现金运钞车是和丽子的爱情宣言
But, because Nishio shot that guard,
可是 因为西尾开枪打了警卫
my perfect plan was ruined.
糟蹋了我的完美的计划
There is no such thing as perfection.
这个世界上没有完美
There will always be a loose cog.
肯定哪里的齿轮没有咬紧
If you force it to work,
就这样硬要动的话
maybe you'll ruin everything.
什么都有可能不行的
You still have to reset, go back to normal,
重新启动一次  回到正常状态
and try hard to right the wrongs of the past.
挽回努力的部分只能靠这个人了
You're just scared.
你只是害怕啊
Scared of reset.
害怕RESET啊
Maybe you're right.
可能是那样啊
Will it work?
可以了吗
What is this?
这是什么
If we don't stop the time limit, we can't release the IDs either.
是不解除时间的话就不能解开ID吧
Damn it!
可恶
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Are you still not feeling well?
还是不舒服吗
No, I'm all right
不是的
It's okay.
不要紧
Really? If you're not feeling well, let me know, okay?
是吗？ 要是不舒服的话马上说的哦
Okay, I will.
嗯 会说的
Still, Conan didn't come.
结果柯南没有来啊
He must have stayed with Detective Mouri.
果然是跟着毛利侦探啊
Right, he always leave us behind like this.
真是的 只是一个人好狡猾啊
Conan is the best at trying to be a hero alone.
抢功是柯南最擅长的行为了
Have you heard anything from Mouri?
毛利那里有什么消息吗
No.
没有
I see.
是吗
When there's one minute left, I'm going in.
还差一分的时候我就进去
Don't...
不要
I can't leave the kids alone there.
我不能只把孩子们留在那里
That's right.
是啊
It's 9:56. There's no time, Kudo.
9:56 没时间了 工藤
Oh right, he uses a wireless connection.
对了 他用无线连接的
If the wireless connection doesn't work, it may work if we connect it to the cable directly.
如果无线不行的话直接接上电缆也许就可以了
Great, we can make it this way.
好 这样就够得到了
OK, it worked!
OK 解开了
Well done.
干得好
Disable the time limit.
时间解除
Please enter password.
请输入密码
Hey... Password...
密… 密码
Hey, Kudo, this guy...
喂 工藤 这家伙
It's okay. He just passed out.
不要紧 昏过去了而已
Maybe from the shock.
可能是事故的后遗症吧
What is the name of the person you love the most.
你最爱的人名字是？
It's 9:59 now.
59分了
You stay here.
你待在这里
Yes, sir.
是
I was really surprised.
把人家吓了一跳呢
It wasn't a big deal for me.
我可觉得没什么哟
Did you have a good time today?
怎么样 今天玩得开心吗
I wish I could have rode the Super Snake.
没坐上SUPER SNAKE 好不爽
I think that rocket ride was fun too.
那个火箭也似乎很好玩呢
I really want to ride it again.
嗯 真想再坐一次呢
The one Itou loves the most should be Reiko Shimizu.
伊东喜欢的应该是清水丽子
Incorrect password.
密码错误
What? This guy doesn't like Reiko Shimizu?
什么  这家伙喜欢的不是清水丽子吗
Incorrect password. Entry of another incorrect password will result in immediate system shutdown.
密码错误 如果再一次输入错误的话 输入系统将关闭
Who is it? The one Itou loves...
到底是谁 伊东爱的人
Who is it...
到底…
And you always tried to show off when we talked.
他说的都是些自满的话
But, because Nishio shot that guard,
可是 因为西尾开枪打了警备员
my perfect plan was ruined.
糟蹋了我的完美的计划
I got it.
我知道了
What are you typing, Kudo?
你打什么啊 工藤
The time limit has been disabled.
计时器已解除
It's over.
结束了啊
Yeah, it's over now.
啊 这样就行了
Good job, Shinichi.
做得好 新一
Although the time limit has been disabled, I don't know how to deal with the sensors yet.
时限装置虽然解除 区域监控装置还不知道怎么弄
So make sure to collect all of them, Professor.
所以全部都要回收一个都不能漏哦 博士
Okay, I'll do it right now.
好 我马上回收
Kudo, and Hattori.
工藤 还有服部
You two are the best detectives.
你们是最棒的侦探
You're the worst.
你是最差劲的人
Hey, are you all right?
喂 你们没事吧
Here, take off your IDs and put them in here.
来 把ID取下来放到这里面
Huh? Do I have to take it off?
咦？ 要拿下来吗
It's already closing time.
已经到结束的时间啦
Too bad...
好可惜啊
Handkerchief... Handkerchief...
手帕啊手帕
I thought I lost mine.
啊 我还以为掉了
What's this?
这是什么啊
Looks like paint.
像油漆一样的东西
Where did it come from?
在那里沾上的呢
Come on, I'll take it back.
来 回收回收
Oh, well...
啊那个…
We apologize for the inconvenience. The Super Snake is now reopened.
很抱歉为大家造成了麻烦 SUPER SNAKE的修理已经完成
Even though it's already past closing time, we'll run the ride one last time.
虽然已经过了开园时间 不过再为大家开启一次
Great!
太好了
Are you okay, Hattori?
没事吧 服部
Don't worry. Just a scratch.
别担心 这种小伤
But then again, how did he know you were Shinichi Kudo?
话说回来 他为什么会知道你是工藤新一呢
Because of this.
因为这个
This is... your fingerprint?
这个是… 指纹？
Do you remember the chairs in that room?
那个房间的椅子你还记得吗
Ah, because they don't match the the room, I remember it very well.
啊 因为和房间的氛围不配 我记得很牢
I was impressed by the arm rests of the chairs.
我很在意椅子的把手
I guess there were fingerprint recognition systems on the arm rests.
估计椅子的把手里有指纹识别系统
This fingerprint belongs to Shinichi Kudo.
这是工藤新一的指纹
Since the client are blind,
由于委托人的眼睛看不见
It was natural that he thought I was Shinichi Kudo.
所以认为我是工藤新一也是可能的
So that's how it is.
原来是这样啊
Oh no! it's past 10:00!
啊 不好 已经过10点了
It's past 10:00! It's going to explode!
过10点了 要爆炸了
You can take it off now. Your ID belt.
已经解除喽 ID的带子
I mean this one.
是这个
Oh, it's true! Great!
啊 是真的 太好了
I'll take it back.
回收
Hey, wait!
喂 等等
He's really...
真是的
Anyway, after those things were took off, this case is finally closed, huh?
不过那玩意儿一拿下来 事件也总算结束了
Anyway, put me down first.
比起这个 你快把我放下吧
Don't push yourself too hard. You can't walk well yet.
别勉强了 脚不好不是吗
That's right... the best medicine for this kid is to ride on this girl's back.
就是这样的啊 对这小子的伤来说 姐姐背一背就是最好的药了
Don't make fun of me.
别开玩笑了
Childish.
孩子
Inspector, the IDs have all been collected.
警官 ID全部都回收完毕了
I've counted the number.
数目没错
Send them to the Identification Division without anyone noticing.
交给鉴定课不要让大家发觉
Yes, sir.
是
All right! No matter it's the Super Snake or anything else, let's ride on!
好了 管他SUPER SNAKE还是别的什么的 坐上去吧
Hold on tight.
坐好喽
Lucky! We got it all to ourselves!
真好运 这样等于就是我们包下来了
Don't let this scare the crap our of you.
别吓掉裤子哦
Idiot, I won't be scared.
笨蛋 谁会怕啊
Everyone! Hands up!
大家伸手吧
Everyone is too excited, huh?
大家很来劲呢
If you are scared, you don't have to put your hands up.
害怕的话不放开手也行啊
Who is scared?
谁怕了
I'm telling you, I could raise my hands very, very high....
我的话  手可是会放的很开的哦
This kid stuff...
这种小儿科的东西…
That's too funny, Heiji.
太有意思了 平次
Hey! You guys!
喂！ 说你们呢
Genta! Take it off! Genta!
元太  快拿下来啊  元太
What are you doing? Take it off! We'll be outside the area limit when it goes out over the sea!
你在干什么 快点脱下来 这样驶向大海就要超出区域了
Genta!
元太
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 在什么啊
Don't move, or you'll die.
别动 再动你就没命了
Yes...
好！
Kudo!
工藤
Back there!
在后面
That's terrible!
糟了
Hurry!
快去
No! Stop him!
不行 快阻止他
You can't do that. The bars are all linked together.
不行的 这里的保险杠都是连锁的
If one is broken...
一个坏了的话…
all of the bars will be affected.
会连累到大家的保险杠
Wow, great!
啊 太棒了
They even had fireworks.
没想到还能开到烟花
It must be an extra service.
还真是额外服务呢
Somehow, I didn't feel happy at all.
我好像一点也不开心
Why is that guy here?
为什么那家伙在这里
He's been with us since the investigation started, right?
搜查开始时就一直在我们身边了吧
Huh?
咦？
What the hell!
真是的
Geez, that Ryu...
龙这家伙
I never thought he would play dead for money.
没想到缺钱缺到去装死啊
He must have been lying
那个时候那家伙说的
about the other two detectives he mentioned at that time.
两个侦探的名字也只是故弄玄虚啊
Did he really need money that much?
他要钱都做到了这个地步了啊
How spineless.
真没志气
Yeah, this is Mouri Detective Agency.
喂 这里是毛利侦探事务所
What? You want me to play in a TV ad?
咦 要我出演广告？
What kind of TV ad?
是什么广告啊
What? For sleeping pills?
什么 安眠药的广告？
It's gonna be easy because I'm always sleeping?
因为是和平常一样就行所以很简单？
Are you kidding me?
不要开玩笑了
Who do you think I am?
你认为我是谁啊
I know it's hard to find a good actor like me, but...
就算再怎么缺演员
What?
什么
That much?
那么多啊？
Yeah! Please let me do it!
啊 务必请让我出演
Yes, yes!
是的 是的
As expected...
果然是这样啊
He really lives up to his name, Sleeping Kogoro.
不愧是沉睡的小五郎啊
My pleasure!
我很乐意